（华纳兄弟影业）
（奥泰梅萨移民拘留中心）
（美国-墨西哥边境）
欢迎
Welcome.
里面估计有250到275人
Our best guess, there's about 250, 275 people in there.
很难数清 可能比这还多
It's hard to count.
等正式行动的时候
We need to be prepared for, like,
我们要做好带走300人的准备
300 people by the time we get there, right?
我们这辆集装箱大卡车
Our cargo container, 18-wheeler,
拖一个集装箱 最多能装160人
That thing only holds 160 people.
还得是人挤人...
I'm talking 'bout crammed in there tight...
前胸贴后背
That's cheek to jowl.
...脸贴脸的
...smashed face to face.
让女人孩子先上车
Women and children first.
听着 那些上不了车的
Listen, whoever's not on with us,
就让他们自己跑
They just run, on foot.
上不了车的 只能自己跑
That's it. If they're not with us, they run.
记住 我们从友谊路撤退
Via de la Amistad, that's our exit route.
它是东西向的 离905公路约一两公里
Runs east-west. It's about one mile from 905.
好的
Right.
你的小车里拉了什么？
What you draggin' in that wagon?
有自制炸药
Listen, I got HMEs.
有发射筒 还有催泪瓦斯
I got mortars, I got tear gas,
你们需要的我都有
I got whatever you guys need,
可我还不清楚计划是什么
But I'm a little unclear as to what the plan is.
能不能说明一下？
I'm gonna need some direction.
没什么不清楚的 我都计划好了
Don't be unclear. I got a plan for us.
什么计划？
Well, what is it?
要我来引开注意力吗？
I mean, you want me to create a diversion?
还是要炸掉什么 你说说
You want me to blow something up? What do you want?
我想让你策划一个隆重出场 帕特 好吗？
I want you to create a show, Pat. Okay?
向所有人宣告革命开始了
This is the announcement of the motherfuckin' revolution.
好
Yeah.
要盛大 要精彩 别让我失望
Make it good. Make it bright. Impress me.
第二小队从这儿走 明白了吗？
Team Two's entrance. We got that?
对 那条路是南北向的
Yep. That runs north and south.
很好 很好
Perfect, perfect, perfect.
- 给帕特拿个对讲机 - 把对讲机给我
- Give Pat a walkie. - Gimme a walkie.
听好 大卡车走费米路直接开到营房去
Big truck coming up Enrico Fermi...
频道五
Channel five.
明白
Copy that.
- 好 讨论结束 行动开始 - 出发
- Yeah! It's game time. No more talking 'bout this. - Let's go!
- 好 我们走 - 赶紧出发吧
- All right, let's go, let's go. - Let's fuckin' go.
【特朗普墙：背景图像为特朗普首任期修建的美墨边境墙 象征美国边境治理策略的显著加强】
都当心点儿
Watch, watch, watch.
跪下 跪舔姿势
Get on your knees, like you 'bout to suck a dick.
门卫搞定了
Gate guard secure.
起床 举起手 起来
Hey, you. Get up. Hands up. Get up.
- 趴下 起床 - 举起手来
- Down. Hey you, get up. - Get your hands up.
- 起来 都给我起床 - 趴在那里
- Wake up. All the way up! - Down on the ground.
举上去 别瞎看
Hands up. Don't look at me.
- 全给我起床 - 起来
- All the way up. - Wake up.
起来 大兵
Wake up, soldier boy.
你死了 进了老娘的生死簿
You died and went to pussy heaven, motherfucker.
把手从脸上拿开 给你验明正身
Put your arms to the side so I can see you.
（西班牙语）醒醒 起床了 都醒醒
（西班牙语）醒一醒 都起来
（西班牙语）卡车在门口 该走了 都起来
（西班牙语）快点儿
（西班牙语）都醒醒
报上名来 野鬼
What's your name, dickhead?
我是史蒂文·勒喉乔上尉
I'm Captain Steven J. Lockjaw.
【勒喉乔：暗指以暴力噤声的铁腕人物】
我叫叛娅·富山 我正式向你们宣战
My name is Perfidia Beverly Hills, and this is a declaration of war.
【叛娅·富山：字面指对富人背叛及反抗】
我们是来纠正你们犯下的错误的
We're here to right your wrongs, motherfucker.
是你们亲手培育了反抗军 这是你自找的
You got an army growin' in your fuckin' guts, and you put it there.
你想不到我会来
You didn't count on me.
真不错
Oh, my God.
你想不到我会反抗
You didn't count on my fight.
我们的主张很明确 边境自由 身体自由
The message is clear. Free borders, free bodies,
【边境与身体自由：主张跨境流动与身体自主权】
选择自由 免于恐惧
free choices, and free from fuckin' fear!
【选择自由与免于恐惧：主张个人决定权与免于胁迫】
小美人儿
Sweet thing.
没听懂吗？
Is this funny?
起来
Get up.
没说你脚
Not on your feet.
我可没让你站起来
Oh, not on your fuckin' feet.
既然你想玩
Since we playin'...
那就硬起来
get it up.
快点儿
Up.
对 硬起来
Yeah. Get it up.
大家快走
Guys, hurry up!
当心 当心
Be careful!
动作都快点儿
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
别磨蹭
Apurarse.
快 快 快
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
但要有序 注意脚下
But be careful! Be careful!
都往里面走
All the way to the back.
真见鬼
Holy shit.
不要停下
Keep it moving now.
起来
Up.
真乖
Good boy.
你喜欢把别人关起来 是吗？
You like lockin' people up, huh?
没错
Oh, yeah.
给我跪下
Get on your fuckin' knees!
马上
Now.
快点儿跪下
Let's go, let's go.
戴上这个
Put it on.
别磨蹭
Let's go!
外勤行动
边境战术应对小组
现在你可以站起来了
Now get the fuck up.
把手举起来 继续硬着
Let's go. Hands up. Keep that dick up.
- 好吧 - 举过头
- All right. - Keep it up.
往外走
The fuck out.
帕特
Pat.
帕特在
Go for Pat.
执行“霹雳”计划
Snap, crackle, pop, baby.
收到
Copy that.
点起来 点起来
Come on, come on!
我们宣战了 下地狱吧
I declare war, motherfucker.
（西班牙语）还瞪我 你跑不了了
（西班牙语）懂吗？
（西班牙语）你们这群混蛋
（西班牙语）你这条恶心的蛆
（西班牙语）当心我把你剁成肉酱
我们很快会再见面的
I'll be seeing you very soon.
但是最好别让我先找到你
Not if I see you first, fuck face.
我们是政治组织 是革命队伍
We are a political organization
不怕监视 不怕偷听
that is free from the eyes, the ears,
最重要的是
and most importantly,
我们不怕帝国主义和法西斯政权的大炮
the weapons of the imperialist state, and this fascist regime!
你们现在是法式七五组织的政治犯
You are a political prisoner of the French 75, motherfuckers!
【法式七五：借用法国革命意象 亦为野战炮与酒名】
由法式七五组织执行关押
You've been captured by the French 75!
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
条子去死吧
Fuck the police!
【美国警察：常被指控滥权 系统性歧视 及过度使用武力】
（西班牙语）革命万岁
走吧
Let's go!
（西班牙语）下地狱去吧 一群吃人的恶鬼
一群畜生
Motherfuckers!
（西班牙语）我们走
（西班牙语）听着 冷静点儿
- 别激动 都冷静一下 - 天啊
- Hold on, y'all, hold on. - Shit. Oh, shit.
（西班牙语）真刺激
你怎么开心的跟过年一样？
Where you get all this energy from?
你说什么？
What are you talkin' about?
今晚穷鬼帕特是我的了
I'm getting Ghetto Pat tonight. I think I like you.
【穷鬼帕特：人物代号 原指贫民区或其居民】
你喜欢黑人女孩吗？
You like Black girls?
喜欢吗？
Yeah?
我喜欢什么？
Do I like what?
你喜欢
You like...
你们觉得呢？他喜欢我吗？
Y'all think he like Black girls? Y'all think he like me?
- 我看他喜欢你 - 我当然喜欢黑人女孩
- I think he does. - 'Course I fuckin' like Black girls!
把子弹都打光
So shoot this shit up!
- 使劲射 - 不然我怎么会在这里
- Let's go! - What the fuck do you think I'm doing here?
- 打破不公 - 我最喜欢黑人女孩了
- Fuck your mother! - You know I like fuckin' Black girls!
你知道我喜欢
You know I like Black girls.
对我说出来 说你爱我
And I love you. You love me? Tell me you love me.
- 我爱你 - 告诉我你爱我
- I love you. - Tell me you fuckin' love me.
别急 要慢慢来
Calm down. Calm the fuck down.
我现在 要做一个闭合的电路
What I'm doing here is I'm creating a closed circuit
这样就能消除外部的静电
to remove any static electricity.
这个东西
And that right there...
叫分流器 看到了吗？
That's a shunt. You see that?
看到了
Yeah.
这就是起爆用的雷管
This is your blasting cap.
就是这东西
Right here.
百威啤酒
你去法院的时候 一定要把电路接好
Very important to keep your cap shunted like this
避免意外引爆 记住了吗？
when you enter the courthouse. You got that?
这个是炸药 这个是你的手机
Here's your main charge. This is your cell phone.
说下去 用手机做什么？
Don't stop. I see the cell phone.
第一步 先打开手机
First thing you're gonna do is you're gonna turn on your cell phone...
不过千万 千万不能
without your...
不能先把雷管接上
without your cap attached...
否则有可能意外引爆
so you don't accidentally detonate your charge.
你还要记得...
You're gonna wanna...
还要记得手放在这里 对吧
You're gonna wanna put your hands here, right?
然后用手握住你的雷管
And then you wanna take your hands and the cap
放入目标地点
and throw it in the circle.
威尔逊参议员 这是对你的警告
Senator Wilson, this is a warning for you.
公共电话
我们在你连任竞选的办公室里
We planted a bomb at the Haymarket office
放了一个炸弹
of your re-election campaign.
我们警告过你不要通告堕胎禁令
We warned you, that abortion ban,
【堕胎权：女性自主决定是否终止妊娠的权利】
可你根本不听
and you didn't wanna fuckin' listen.
所以 为了受苦的姐妹们 我们要行动
So, for my sisters in need, we will strike.
【美国堕胎权：美国曾由宪法保障堕胎权】
【美国堕胎权：但该保障已被最高法院保守派推翻】
大礼敬上
Sincerely yours,
署名是叛娅·富山
Perfidia Beverly Hills, motherfucker.
【美国堕胎权：保守的州纷纷立法限制女性堕胎】
暴力革命是唯一的出路
Revolutionary violence is the only way.
投票是扯淡
No more tellin' me to vote.
忍无可忍
No more tellin' me to overcome.
就算警察拿枪指着我的头 我也无所谓
"Nobody move, nobody get hurt" shit, it doesn't matter.
人人都要付出代价
Everybody pays.
不用费劲找法式七五
Don't even bother lookin' for the French 75.
我们会找你的
We'll find you.
西进银行
- 亲爱的 准备好了吗？ - 好了
- Okay, baby, you ready? - Yeah.
弄好了
All right.
准备就绪 我们走
All right. Let's go.
- 亲爱的 - 怎么了？
- Babe... - Yeah?
我想在爆炸的时候上你
Let's fuck while the bomb go off.
不行
No, babe.
- 来吧 我很饥渴 - 走吧 我们得快走
- Come on, baby. Let's fuck, baby. - Come on, baby, we gotta go.
- 快走 - 来吧 宝贝
- Hurry. - Come on. Come on, baby.
- 就在这里 - 不行 我们得赶紧走
- Let's fuck, baby. - No, baby. We gotta go.
快走
Come on. Come on.
快来吧 宝贝
Come on, baby.
快走吧 宝贝
来看着我 别急
Hold on. Wait.
还有两分钟就要爆炸了
Bomb goes off in two minutes.
联信银行
趴下
Get down.
我们走 把他们带走
Bring 'em all!
快点儿 都快走
Come on!
别出声 懂了吗？
Don't say a fuckin' word, okay?
听懂没有？
You understand me?
都拿上
Get the rest!
对了
Oh, yeah.
我们走 快走
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
都快一点儿 快走快走
Come on, come on!
不许动
Stay right there. Don't you fuckin' move.
抓住他 我们走
Grab him! Let's go.
一步也别动 听到了吗？
Stay right fucking there, okay?
要是敢动 就让你脑袋开花
You fucking move, I'll blow your fucking head off.
一看就是个女白领
Regular-working White girl.
去大显身手吧
Now do your thing.
一
战
再
我们准备了两套遥控器 爆破两个地点
We have two devices for two locations,
之间相隔三个街区
set three blocks apart.
梅·韦斯特负责安装行政大楼的炸弹
Mae West completes her device in the administration building,
【梅·韦斯特：借用好莱坞性感女星之名 暗指利用种族与外表特权作为渗透工具】
我和叛娅负责法院的遥控器安装
Perfidia and I take the courthouse.
炸弹已提前放好
Bombs are planted,
遥控装好后 晚上七点下班后远程引爆
devices are detonated by remote at 7 p.m. after hours.
从那一刻开始
From here on in,
就要一战再战
it's one battle after another.
【译注：白人已过安检 黑人则面临额外搜身】
禁止吸烟
你想让我做什么？
What do you want me to do?
让你为我做最坏的事
I want you to do your worst.
你想炸掉什么都可以
You can blow up anything you want,
我根本不在乎
it doesn't make any difference to me.
我要我的帽子 还有我的枪
I want my hat. And my gun.
要是你不想被人告发
If you wanna keep doing what you're doing,
那就今晚11点 到春歧途酒店找我
You'll meet me at the Primrose Path, 2300.
♪ 小战士
♪ Soldier boy ♪
♪ 哦 我的小战士
♪ Oh, my little soldier boy ♪
♪ 我会对你忠诚 ♪
♪ I'll be true to you ♪
♪ 你是我的初恋
♪ You were my first love ♪
♪ 也是我最后的爱人 ♪
♪ And you'll be my last love ♪
能不能慢慢来？我想把鞋脱了
Can we go slowly? Wanna take my shoes off.
♪ 我永远不会让你伤心 ♪
♪ I will never make you blue ♪
闭起...
Shut...
...嘴来
...up.
♪ 我会对你忠诚 ♪
♪ I'll be true to you ♪
♪ 在这个世界上
♪ In the whole world ♪
我进出自由 对吧？
You're gonna let me go, right?
♪ 你只能爱一个女孩
♪ You can love but one girl ♪
是 长官
Yes, ma'am!
♪ 让我做那个女孩吧
♪ Let me be the one girl ♪
♪ 因为我会对你忠诚 ♪
♪ For I'll be true to you ♪
太帅了
Holy shit!
看到了吗？姐是疤面煞星
Bitch, I felt like Tony Montana!
【《疤面煞星》（1983）：指像主角东尼·蒙大拿那样的权力与野心】
没错
Yeah!
看看
Fuck!
厉害
Yes!
打得太爽了
It's cathartic.
你说姐这个逼...
This pussy right here...
你说下面那个？
That one?
干什么用的？
What's it for?
- 打仗 - 快活
- War! Bitch. - Um... Fun!
不对 错了
Nah.
这不是用来快活的
The pussy ain't for fun.
你看这个 开枪才叫快活
This is the fun. The guns is the fuckin' fun.
咱们的身体就是武器
Pussy is the fucking weapon.
你看
I mean...
我知道
I see it.
那一套白人中产
A White-bred,
市侩庸俗 恶心透顶的公司文化
philistine, asshole corporate culture,
它唯一的目的
whose only end
就是打更多广告 捞更多钱
is to perfect the science of advertising.
我跟你说实话
But I ain't gonna hold ya, bitch.
他要是敢对我不好
If he treats me different after I drop
等这个小东西从我肚子里爬出来
this motherfucker thing inside my stomach, bitch,
我可不忍着 你看我宰了他
we gonna have a fuckin' problem. Kill him, too.
宝贝 别这样
Bae, stop.
看我敢不敢
I'll kill him dead!
趁他还没打倒我
Before he beats me!
说什么呢 姐们儿？
What the fuck? That...
她好像不知道自己怀孕了一样
It's like she doesn't even realize she's pregnant.
那就是孩子爸爸 长得跟其他白巧克力一样
Some other white chocolate daddy over there and all this shit.
【白巧克力爹：俚语 黑人妻子讥讽性称呼白人丈夫】
说得对
You right.
你知道我的意思吧？
You feel me? No...
就是这样 拿起一个 放下去
Okay, so put one up and down.
好的
Okay.
对 这就是说 我是庄家
Okay, so that means...I'm the house.
你和我女儿一点都不般配
You know, you are so unsuitable for my daughter.
我？
Me?
对 你
Yeah, you.
真可笑
And that's hilarious.
我不...
I don't...
我女儿来自的家族 几代人都是革命者
My child comes from a whole line of revolutionaries.
而你一脸茫然
And you look so lost.
她大步向前 你却沉溺当下
She's a runner, and you a stump.
这孩子你打算怎么办？
What are you gonna do about this baby? Hm?
我只是想被人看见 还有
No, I just, I wanna feel seen and...
被人爱 被欣赏
loved and appreciated.
我怀孩子整整九个月
I fuckin' carried her nine months.
现在他却整天只知道围着宝宝转
And now he can just, gets to fuckin' walk around...
看见孩子就开心得不得了
and just swoonin' all fuckin' day.
就好像 他只爱女儿一个人
It's like she's his only girl.
我就是空气 是一块肉
Like, I just no longer exist. I'm just a fuckin' piece of meat.
有时候我觉得自己疯了
And sometimes, I feel crazy,
我居然会嫉妒自己的宝宝 这正常吗？
'cause I'm just like...am I weird for being jealous of my baby?
我感觉没人关心我 没人爱我
I don't fuckin' feel seen. I don't feel love.
我肯定变丑了
I feel fuckin' ugly.
我的胸口疼 我几乎都没有奶水了
My nipples hurt. I can barely fucking produce milk.
我…
You know, I...
我感觉糟透了
I'm not okay.
亲爱的 你大晚上去哪儿？
Baby, where do you think you're goin', huh?
穿成这样上哪儿去？
Where you goin' like that?
别跟我说话 我想去哪儿就去哪儿
Stop talkin' to me. I go as I please.
你看我们都成家了
You realize that we're a family now, right?
用不着闹革命了
You don't have to do this anymore.
你知道我说过 我为自己而活
You realize I put myself first, right?
你就是害怕这一点
And that's what you scared of.
我们都有孩子了 总不会忘了吧？
We have her now. You do get that, right?
首先 我为自己活 其次 你的话老掉牙了
I put myself first, and I reject your lack of originality.
天啊 说我老掉牙
God, my lack of originality.
请你不要再胡扯了好吗？
Will you stop with all this bullshit?
别再闹了 你和我成家了
Would you stop it? We're a goddamn family.
你有责任照顾孩子
You have her to take care of.
你以为你还能去哪儿？
Where the hell do you think you're goin'?
好啦 宝宝
It's okay, baby.
没事的 不哭了
It's okay, baby. It's okay.
宝宝不哭 没事的
不要给我灌输你的想法
This is a new consciousness.
我的想法？
New consciousness?
对
Yeah.
我可不是孩子保姆
I'm not your udder buddy.
我也不是你妈
I'm not your mother.
你想要掌控我
You want your power over me,
就像你们男人总想掌控一切
The same reason you want your power over the world.
你和你那玻璃心的大男子主义
You and your crumblin' male ego...
永远不会成为这场革命的战友
Will never do this revolution like me.
所以请滚出我的房子
Fuck outta here.
那你还是闹革命去吧 再见
Do the revolution, baby. Go do it.
你有孩子是吗？
You got a baby?
对 有孩子
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
男孩女孩？
Male? Female?
是个女孩
She's a girl.
叫什么？
What's her name?
夏琳
Charlene.
像黑妞的名字
Sounds like a Black girl's name.
你喜欢黑妞吗？
You like Black girls?
我超喜欢
I love 'em.
我爱死她们了
I love them!
跪下
Get on your knees.
给我跪下
Get on your fuckin' knees.
- 别动 举起手来 - 快点儿
- Don't move. - Now!
很好
Good job.
都脸朝下趴好
Get your noses in the carpet.
我叫贱女姜戈
My name is Junglepussy.
【贱女姜戈：象征游击式反抗与自由 以挑衅性名称作为反制标识】
看 这就是权力
This is what power looks like.
看清楚了吗？
See my face?
装进去
Put it there.
- 我们就像《辣姐妹》一样 - 举起手
- This some Set It Off shit. - Hands up.
【《辣姐妹》（1996）：四位女性因贫困与不公筹划抢劫】
我不要命 我只要你们的钱
I don't want you. I just want your money.
你们的钱 会变成我的武器
Your money pays for my artillery,
我的补给
my supplies,
我开的车子
my transportation,
我的炸药
my dynamite,
我的宣言
my message.
我就是黑人力量的化身
I am what Black Power looks like.
看清楚了吗？
See my face?
看清楚 我们是法式七五
See my face! I'm the French 75!
不要乱动
Stop moving.
我说别动 听见了吗？
Stop fucking moving.
拜托你别动了 好吗？
Stop fuckin' moving, man.
【译注：黑人既为受压迫者
亦可能作为体制中尽职的执行者
突显复杂的道德两难】
我们走
All right, go.
站住 警察
Stop! Police!
拷住左手
Cuff the left arm, please.
这个部门不会对谁网开一面
This department doesn't do any special favors,
尤其是黑妞
especially for Black girls.
你杀人了 这还是轻的
You're a killer, and that's the least of it.
判个三十年
You'll do 30,
或者四十年
40 years in prison.
可惜你不认识什么大人物
It's too bad you don't know anybody with sway.
你可以救我
You can save me.
因为你爱上我了
Because you're in love with me.
是的
Yes.
你没有我就活不下去
And you can't live without me.
能抱抱我吗？
Can you hold me?
不如我让联邦政府
I can give you the embrace
给你个拥抱吧
of the federal government.
你得说出他们在哪儿 列个名单
You've gotta tell me where they are, and name names.
不要这样
Don't do this.
你不想坐牢 就得交代名单
You have to name names, or you're gonna go to prison.
明妮阿姨 有儿童座椅或者背带吗？
Miss Minnie, do you have a car seat or a carrier?
没有 亲爱的
No, no, no, baby.
这两个是我做的配对器
These are two scanners that I've made.
这个能播放乐曲A
This one plays Melody A.
这个能播放乐曲B
This one plays Melody B.
只要它们之间的距离小于二三百米
Together, they go off within 200 or 300 yards of each other,
就会自动同步 合奏主旋律
they sync up, they'll play a main melody.
- 主旋律 - 两人各拿一个配对器
- Main melody. - Okay? Somebody else has one of these,
就能识别出对方是自己人
you both know the tune, you'll be able to find each other.
- 这个叫信任配对器 - 好
- This is a trust device. - Right.
使用规则第一条
Okay? Rule of thumb with these scanners,
如果你见到拿着这个配对器的人
find somebody else out there and they happen to have one of these,
就无条件信任那个人 好吗？
trust them with your life, okay?
这个我不会随便给人的
I'm not passing these out to just anybody.
- 她可能是饿了 - 得带上毛巾
- She might be hungry. - I need some towels.
- 好啦 不哭了 - 明妮阿姨 拿几条毛巾好吗？
- Yeah. All right. - Miss Minnie, can you get me some towels?
好的 怎么啦？
Okay. What's wrong?
知道了 我们马上就出发
I know. We're going.
得有手机...
Get a phone or don't...
要是非得用手机 就用模拟机
If you gotta get a cell, make it 1G. The early analogue stuff,
【1G：1970年代末兴起的模拟手机信号 提供模拟语音移动服务】
现在没人监控1G的信号了
they don't scan those frequencies anymore.
- 所以很安全 不然就别用手机 - 好
- You'll be fine. Otherwise, no phones. - Okay.
只要有信号 我们就能联系上
If the towers are up, we're gonna be able to find each other in any case.
- 明白 - 记住这个信封里的东西
- All right. - Memorize everything in this envelope.
记牢之后就烧掉
Burn it when you're done.
不要直接去归援十字市
You don't go to Baktan Cross right away.
【归援十字市：虚构城镇 意为慈爱包容并予以支援】
先去丹佛市
You go to Denver first.
在那边住上一星期
You spend a week in Denver.
在这一星期里
While you're in Denver,
误导追查方向
plant those decoys.
留好你要去哪里的假线索后
When that's all clear and that job is done,
再去归援十字市
then you go on to Baktan Cross.
这是你们的新名字和社保号码
These are the new names and socials.
好 那我们现在是谁？
Right, so who are we supposed to be here?
你们是鲍勃·弗格森和薇拉·弗格森
You are Bob and Willa Ferguson.
【新身份：常见白人名字 便于融入与不被怀疑】
这是上个月去世的一对母子的名字
It's a mother and son who died in childbirth last month.
所以我们要假冒死人？
So we're pretending to be dead folks?
要是你这么想 那就是这样
If you wanna think about it that way, yes,
但要是不这样做 死的人会更多
but there are bigger deaths down the line if we don't do this.
我希望你能顾全大局
I want you to think big picture here, all right?
- 好 - 这件事比你我都重要
- Right. Right. - This is bigger than you or I.
也比去世的弗格森母子更重要
This is bigger than the original Bob and Willa Ferguson, okay?
你们快一点
Guys, you better hurry up.
好
Yeah.
欢迎来到真实世界 鲍勃
Welcome to the world, Bob.
出发吧
Let's go!
顾全大局
Big picture.
明白 是啊
Got it. Yeah.
好的
Okay.
好的 没问题
Okay. Okay.
你很安全
You're safe.
- 我得走了 添麻烦了 - 好吧 你走吧
- I gotta go. I'm sorry, okay? - Okay.
- 慢走 - 拜托你们了
- I know you do, but... - I'm sorry.
走吧 你确定不把宝宝留下来吗？
I know, but you not sure you wanna let her stay with us?
我得赶快走了
I gotta go, I gotta go!
我知道了 你路上小心
I know, I know. But travel in grace.
天啊 保佑他们平安吧
Oh, my God.
帮我抱一下
Here. Hold her.
- 好 给我吧 - 谢谢
- All right, I got her, I got her. - Thanks.
- 好孩子 过来吧 - 给你
- Come on, baby girl, come on.
当心头
Watch her head.
好了
All right.
爱你
Love you.
也爱你
I love you.
保重
Take care.
- 你也是 - 走了
- Stay safe. - Okay.
回到家了
Home sweet home.
这些你都听过 但我要再强调一遍
We've been through all this before, but I've gotta go through it one more time.
不要联系任何人 特别是你那帮花瓶姐妹
No contact ever with anyone from Josie and the Pussycats
【猫女乐队：源自美国漫画与动画 并有同名乐团 故事中被用作贬称】
别去找你过去的同伙
or any of your former associates.
不能见家人朋友
No family. No friends.
绝不要犯罪
Don't commit any crimes.
需要作证的时候 我们会找你的
You will testify when we need you to testify.
你的当务之急是找一份工作
Look, first order of business, find a job.
养活自己
Pay your bills.
- 听懂了吗？ - 嗯
- You good? - Mm-hmm.
欢迎成为主流美国人
Welcome to mainstream America.
革命一开始 我们与恶魔作战
Every revolution begins fightin' demons
到头来 却开始自相残杀
but motherfuckers just end up fightin' themselves.
员工通道
顾客止步
举起手来
Hands up!
举起手来 手放在后脑勺上
Put your hands up over your head!
把你的手举起来
She's in the back!
高一点儿
Get your hands up! Higher!
他执行任务英勇无畏
For valor in the line of duty...
最终成功让暴力团伙法式七五组织
and bringing justice to the vigilante group...
受到了法律的制裁
known as the French 75,
我们特此表彰
We are here to award
史蒂文·勒喉乔警官
Steven J. Lockjaw
为他颁发贝德福德·福雷斯特荣誉奖章
with the Bedford-Forrest Medal of Honor.
【内森·贝德福德·福雷斯特：白人至上主义者 三K党领导人】
老娘对你没性趣
16年之后
Sixteen years later,
世界没有改变多少
the world had changed very little.
（日语）平安二段
你的呼吸不对
You're not breathing.
再来一遍
Let's do it again.
♪ 日子不好过
♪ Times are hard
♪ 你害怕付账
♪ You're afraid to pay the fee ♪
♪ 于是你找了个
♪ So you find yourself somebody ♪
♪ 愿意免费干活的人 ♪
♪ Who can do the job for free ♪
（日语）平安二段
♪ 当你需要爱和关心
♪ When you need a bit of lovin' ♪
♪ 因为那个人不在家
♪ 'Cause your man is out of town ♪
♪ 于是你找到我
♪ That's the time you get me runnin' ♪
♪ 你知道我会在你身边 ♪
♪ And you know I'll be around ♪
♪ 我真是傻瓜 愿意为你干脏活 ♪
♪ I'm a fool to do your dirty work, oh yeah ♪
♪ 从此我再也不想 为你干脏活 ♪
♪ I don't wanna do your dirty work no more ♪
♪ 我真是傻瓜 愿意为你干脏活 ♪
♪ I'm a fool to do your dirty work, oh yeah ♪
♪ 点燃蜡烛 锁上大门
♪ Light the candle put the lock upon the door ♪
♪ 你让女佣提前回家
♪ You have sent the maid home early ♪
♪ 过去你也总是这样 ♪
♪ Like a thousand times before ♪
♪ 就像古老游戏棋盘上 角落里的城堡
♪ Like the castle in its corner in a medieval game ♪
高中
♪ 我预感会有大麻烦
♪ I foresee terrible trouble ♪
历史课？
History class?
♪ 却还是留下来 ♪
♪ And I stay here just the same ♪
对
Mm-hmm.
♪ 我真是傻瓜 愿意为你干脏活 ♪
♪ I'm a fool to do your dirty work, oh yeah ♪
但愿你们教的是正经历史
Teachin' the right kind of history, I hope.
那是林肯？
Lincoln.
【林肯：美国第16任总统 以废奴与维护联邦统一被视为国父级人物】
对
Mm-hmm.
墙上挂的伟人真不少啊
I see you got all the greats here, huh?
当然
Oh, yeah.
他打的什么主意？
What were his intentions?
那边还有老罗斯福总统
Got Teddy Roosevelt over there. You got...
希望没漏掉美菲战争的事儿
Hope you teach about the Philippines and all that.
【美菲战争（1899–1902）：美接管菲律宾引发的反殖民战争 伴随大量平民伤亡与殖民统治争议】
这个年级不会细讲的
We don't get all into the details just yet,
- 但也不会刻意隐瞒 - 应该多讲
- but we don't hide from them, either. - You should.
就应该告诉他们真相
You should. Gotta tell the truth.
我看还有
And then you got...
三K党的大头目
the Grand Wizard over there, right?
【大头目：三K党成立于富兰克林逝世75年后 台词为演员即兴讽刺】
本杰明·富兰克林
Mr. Benjamin Franklin.
我们的国父啊
Forefather.
可恶的奴隶主
Fuckin' slave owner.
那个...
You...
抱歉 教室里不能抽烟
I'm afraid you can't do that here in the classroom.
- 真是到处都有可恶的奴隶主 - 谢谢配合
- Fuckin' slave owners everywhere. - Thanks.
好吧
Well,
总体来说 薇拉在学校表现相当好
Overall, to get into it, Willa's doing really great.
她很自信 也有领导力
She's a confident leader.
她还努力学习
She works hard.
看得出来
You can tell that she actually
她是真心想做一个好学生
cares about being a good student, you know?
她每天来学校都活力十足
She enters class each day ready to work,
期待着学知识
Full of energy.
其他学生都很佩服她
The other students really admire her, um...
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我这眼泪只是...
If I get emotional, it's just um...
喜极而泣
Tears of joy, that's all.
哦
Oh.
我能看出你现在很激动
I see this is very emotional for you.
我不知道
I don't know...
说实话 薇拉一直没有妈妈
You know, Willa grew up without her mom.
她妈妈在她很小的时候死了
Her mom died when she was very young.
是这样啊
Oh. I see.
薇拉从没见过妈妈？
So Willa never knew her mother?
没有 从来没见过
No. She never did.
这姑娘太不容易了
That can be very hard on a young woman.
（警告 围栏已通电）
（西班牙语）请帮忙
（西班牙语）帮帮忙
长官 斯金纳中尉要见您
Sir, I have Lieutenant Skinner here to speak with you.
斯金纳 有什么事？
What do you got, Skinner?
长官
Sir,
优进部副主任奉上级命令 要与您谈话
Deputy Director of Progress has orders to speak to you, sir.
已经安排了车 今晚六点送您过去
Your transportation is set for 1800 hours, sir.
知道他有什么事吗？
You know what this is about, Skinner?
- 不知道 我... - 没事 我猜到了
- No, sir, I'm... - Well, I think I do.
你可以出去了 中尉
That'll be all, Lieutenant.
欢迎 上校 请跟我来
Welcome, Colonel. Please follow me.
通往酒店大堂
（州长套房）
让人告诉我妻子
Have somebody tell my wife
我几分钟后就下去
I'll be down in a few minutes.
勒喉乔上校 谢谢你过来
Colonel Lockjaw, thanks for coming.
您好 桑迪先生
Sandy, great to see you.
认识一下维道尔·司空伯顿
Let me introduce you to Virgil Throckmorton.
维道尔 这是勒喉乔上校
Virgil, Colonel Steve Lockjaw.
我叫史蒂文·勒喉乔
Steve Lockjaw.
你好 上校
How do you do, Colonel?
很高兴认识您
My pleasure, sir.
抱歉 还让你偷偷摸摸从后门进来
Yeah, I'm sorry about all the espionage at the back entrance.
我女儿要结婚 大家都穿着礼服
My daughter's getting married and dress was formal.
我们不想让你不自在
So, we didn't want you to feel out of place.
我完全理解 先生
Perfectly understandable, sir.
请坐吧
Please, sit.
尚恩·米切尔向你问好
Shane Mitchell sends a hello.
尚恩老大 他还在建车库吗？
The big dog. He still building out that garage?
我看他永远都建不完
The construction project that never ends.
总会完工的 请您替我带个好
I'm sure he'll get it done. Will you give him my best?
- 好 - 谢谢
- Will do. - Thank you.
从里奥杜尔特过来顺利吗？
How was your journey from Rio Duarte?
很顺利
Fine, sir.
你在那边干得不错
You're doing great work down there.
谢谢您 先生
Thank you very much, sir.
移民就像汹涌的潮水
Each and every day is hand-to-hand combat
每天都是一场硬仗 对吗？
in the spread of uncontrolled migration, isn't it?
您说得没错
Yes, it is, sir.
是啊
Yeah.
有人说“解决移民 拯救地球”
Well, "You wanna save the planet, you start with immigration."
完全正确 先生
That's exactly right, sir.
这是你说的
You said that.
几年前卧石行动结束后说的
A few years back, after Squatting Pebble.
我听说你对我们感兴趣
I understand you've expressed an interest in us.
是 先生
Yes, sir, I have.
你是不是很荣幸
And does it honor you
能被提名加入我们的俱乐部？
to be considered for membership in our club?
我深感荣幸 先生
It's a very deep honor, sir.
当然是这样
Yes, it is.
史蒂文 我们在过去几年呢
Steve, we have, in the past,
招募了一些军方成员加入俱乐部
Offered membership to certain members of the military.
我们发现他们的
We found their...
实战经验和专业战术相当有用
Tactical battlefield expertise to be quite useful.
你看 我们和你的目标是一致的
Now, our aim and your aim is the same.
及时发现危险的疯子 恨国者
To find dangerous lunatics, haters
地痞流氓 及时制止
And punk trash and stop them.
再也不会有人闹事
No more lunatics.
我不知道你有没有听说
Now, I'm not sure if you've heard or not,
吉姆·克林格去世了
but Jim Kringle passed away.
【克林格：意为耶稣小孩 为英语中圣诞老人的别称】
我听到了消息
Oh, I did hear that, yes.
俱乐部有空缺了
This means an opening.
上校 我可以毫不夸张地说
Colonel, I don't think I'm being immodest when I say
如果能够加入圣诞先驱俱乐部
that joining the Christmas Adventurers Club
你就正式成为了高尚的人
means that you are a superior man.
你不是最优秀 最聪明的人
No, not the best man, not the most intelligent,
也不是最见多识广和智慧的人
The most sophisticated, or the wisest.
你只是比其他人更优越 更高尚
It just means that you are superior to other human beings,
当然你会得到财富 交到最好的朋友
And you shall never want for riches or the greatest of friends.
我们是独立运作 行事也可以机动灵活
Now, we report to ourselves with a freedom to be creative
省略一些繁琐的程序
and cut through layers of bureaucracy.
我们信奉金科玉律
We live by the Golden Rule,
目标是与志同道合的伙伴们一起
in a network of like-minded men and women
让世界变得更安全 更纯净
dedicated to makin' the world safe and pure.
如果有人认为
What would you say to someone who believes
你在种族净化行动中
that you have been soft
表现出软弱动摇 你会怎么说？
in your duty to racial purification?
我会说
I would say
说这样话的人不配活在社会上
they are a liar who has no business in society.
也不配活在地球上
Or on the planet, for that matter. Mm.
你现在有配偶吗？
Do you presently live with a spouse?
没有
No, sir.
你有没有因为心理健康问题 咨询过医生？
Have you ever consulted with a mental health professional?
没有
No, sir.
你有没有拖欠债务
Have you ever had any bills or debts
被人追债？
turned over to a collection agency?
我买过一辆水上摩托
Well, I did purchase a jet ski.
是悄羽蜂速238那个型号的升级款
It was an evolution of the old Hummingbird Whisperdoo 238.
叫做疾爆海豚335
Called the Dynamite Dolphin 335.
它性能有缺陷
It was defective.
我就拒绝了付款 但我一点也不后悔
I abstained from payment. I'd do it again. I have no regrets.
好的
Okay.
你有没有公开参与过
Have you ever knowingly engaged
任何针对美国的恐怖活动？
in any acts of terrorism against this country?
没有
No, sir.
你有没有经历过跨种族的恋爱关系？
Have you ever engaged in an interracial relationship?
没有
No, sir.
你是美国出生的非犹太人？
And you are American-born by gentile?
是的
Yes, sir.
有一点我要说清楚
Now, to avoid any misunderstanding,
你申请加入俱乐部期间
we require absolute secrecy
必须对此事完全保密
through the initiation process
这是为了测试你的无私和忠诚
to judge how serious and unselfish you are.
- 明白吗？ - 嗯
- You understand? - Mm-hmm.
另外 想要成为候选成员
And to be considered to a vote,
你必须自愿接受一项背景审查
you must submit to a voluntary vulnerability study.
用来查明你个人可能有的任何问题
This identifies anything problematic in your character.
我能有什么问题吗？
What could be a problem?
我不知道
I don't know.
你有问题吗？
What could be a problem?
绝对不会有
Absolutely nothing.
我们需要了解你是否可靠
We wanna know who we're standing with.
当然
Sure.
审查是由
Now,
宗审委员会做的全套纯血美国白人背景审查
It's a Double Yankee White Inquisitions Completum.
所以 如果你怀疑自己的
So if you have any doubt as to your ability
身体和品格无法胜任
to qualify in body or character
圣诞先驱俱乐部成员一职
as a member of the Christmas Adventurers Club,
请你现在就提出来
now you have an opportunity to say so.
你要放弃申请吗？
Do you wish to withdraw?
不 先生
No, sir.
你愿意接受审查吗？
Do you submit yourself?
是的 我愿意接受审查
Yes, sir. I submit myself.
非常好
Very well, then.
我和桑迪要去切蛋糕了
Now Sandy and I have to get down to cut the cake.
恭喜您 祝您女儿新婚快乐
Congratulations on your daughter's wedding.
谢谢你
Thank you.
保持联系
We'll be in touch.
谢谢
Thank you.
史蒂文
Steve.
谢谢您 桑迪先生
Thank you, sir. Thank you, Sandy.
“你们也许已经看清了
Maybe starting to see how corrupt to the core
“这场闹剧腐烂到骨子里了”
this whole fucking charade is.
“我们伟大的民主共和政府
This great, noble experiment in self-government.
“被亿万富豪收买出卖 随意操纵
Bought and sold by billionaires.
“那群达沃斯佬
The Davos crowd.
【达沃斯佬：出席达沃斯论坛的精英 意指脱离民众的权力阶层】
“都是公开种族主义者 信奉钟形理论的纳粹”
Openly racist, fucking Bell Curve Nazis.
【《钟形曲线》（1994）：争议著作 结论主张智力与种族相关】
“同志们 民主要沉睡了 道晚安吧”
It's bedtime for democracy, comrades. Good night.
“你感觉自己的心智在被侵蚀吗？
So you're feeling like maybe your mind is starting to erode? Good.
“我们来听听其他电台是怎么说的”
B-Q-W-5-L-P-A, go ahead.
“我们的斗争已经开始了
This is happening on the ground
“我们要有意识 有组织
through coordinated effort,
“有策略地反抗压迫”
And strategic lines of resistance...
“我们要每天团结一致 并肩战斗
Every day, working through dedicated teamwork
“让那些大资本家
to take it directly
“见识到革命的力量”
to the capitalist overlords,
“别忘了资本家每时每刻都在吸我们的血”
Who are extracting value from your life this very second.
“继续”
Go ahead.
“你们以为在网上喊喊口号
What, you think this is Facebook?
“发发朋友圈就是斗争吗？”
This is gonna happen on your Instagram?
“挂个话题标签就能胜利吗？”
It's gonna happen on a hashtag somewhere?
“不是这样的”
I think not.
“斗争的时候 也请不要忘记
And don't forget, while you're doing it,
“这个国家应当给予外来者庇护”
that this is a nation that gives asylum.
这些事情不是孤立的
Don't think they're separate.
要联系起来看 应该要...
Don't break them apart. They're not...
你要干什么？
What the fuck?
通告 通告 重要通告
"QST, QST, QST!
所有庇护站点 请注意
Attention, all sanctuary stations.
“倔山羊被风吹走了”
Billy Goat is in the wind.
重复“倔山羊被风吹走了”
Repeat, Billy Goat is in the wind.
立即执行“霹雳”计划
Implement plan Snap, Crackle, Pop.
重复 执行“霹雳”计划
Repeat, plan Snap, Crackle, Pop.
Repeat, implement plan Snap, Crackle, Pop."
“通告 通告 重要通告
QST, QST, QST!
“所有庇护站点 请注意”
Attention, all sanctuary stations.
“‘倔山羊被风吹走了’
Billy Goat is in the wind.
“重复 ‘倔山羊被风吹走了’”
Repeat, Billy Goat is in the wind.
“立即执行‘霹雳’计划
Implement plan Snap, Crackle, Pop.
“重复 执行‘霹雳’计划”
Repeat, plan Snap, Crackle, Pop.
你好啊
What's up, my man?
人带来了吗？
You got my guy?
车里有痕迹吗？
Any SSE in the car?
- 没有 - 好
- No. - No?
里奥杜尔特
营地最高戒备
给我出来 人渣
Come here, dirtbag.
霍华德·萨默威尔
Howard Sommerville.
你好吗？
How are you?
很好
Good.
“法式七五组织”
The French 75.
“抵抗运动”
The Resistance.
“外来土狼”
The Gringo Coyote?
“倔山羊”
Billy Goat?
你查的挺细啊
Done your homework.
很好
Good.
看看周围 好好看看
Take a look around. Take it all in.
需要什么吗？
Do you need anything?
不需要
I'm fine.
要喝水吗？
A drink?
不用了
I'm okay.
你还活着 这是好事
You're still alive. That's a good sign, right?
大概是吧
Seem to be.
对 你知道为什么吗？
Yeah. Do you know why you're still alive?
那要问你
You tell me.
那我就说了
I will tell you.
我需要你告诉我夏琳的信息
I need you to tell me where Baby Charlene is,
她现在叫什么？住在哪儿？
what's her name, where does she live?
我需要知道“火箭男”住在哪里
I need to know where The Rocket Man lives.
他现在叫什么？
I need to know his name.
- 好吧 - 我说的是“穷鬼帕特”
- Okay. - Ghetto Pat.
好吧 我愿意合作
Okay. I can cooperate.
他们一个叫摩登原始人
Their names are Fred Flintstone
一个叫欢乐时光
and Arthur Fonzarelli
住在天涯边海角上
and their address is Alpha Centauri.
【被审问者故意报出的流行文化虚构姓名】
太幽默了 我喜欢
I love it. I love it.
他自己都泥菩萨过河了
Motherfucker's sittin' on plastic in a container,
还不忘讲笑话
he's still got jokes.
我只想让你知道 我不害怕
I just want you to know that I'm not scared.
我很佩服你
I appreciate that.
如果换成是我 我也不会害怕
If I was in your shoes, I wouldn't be scared, either.
只是不知道你妹妹会不会害怕
I just don't know if your sister would feel that way.
他妹妹叫什么来着？
What's his sister's name?
帕梅拉
Pamela.
不讲笑话了吗？
Oh, no more jokes?
他们叫什么？住在哪儿？
What are their names and where do they live?
他们叫鲍勃·弗格森和薇拉·弗格森
Their names are Bob and Willa Ferguson.
住在归援十字市
They're up in Baktan Cross.
归援十字市
Baktan Cross.
找个理由让我去那边出任务
Make me a reason to deploy in that town.
- 打击贩毒和拉丁裔移民 - 明白
- Drugs and tacos. - Got it.
帮我搜集一些当地情报 就是
And get all the intel on the gathering spots,
小年轻都喜欢去的地方
the hotspots for teenyboppers.
遵命
On it.
小牧
Shep.
Shep. Hey,
过来 到这儿来
come here, come here.
去哪儿啦？
Where'd you...
到这儿来
Come, come with me.
你开不开心呀？
How ya doin'?
去捡 小牧
Get it! Shep!
小牧
Shep.
各位 欢迎参与铁踏行动
Gentlemen, this is Operation Boot Heel.
行动地点是归援十字市
Our AO is Baktan Cross.
这是一座庇护城市
This is a sanctuary city
到处是臭烘烘的拉丁裔
full of thousands of wet 'n stinkies.
我们的行动必须要快
We have a TST operation
抓捕两名重要目标
to capture two HVIs.
成年男性鲍勃·弗格森
Adult male, Bob Ferguson.
少女薇拉·弗格森
Female juvenile, Willa Ferguson,
16岁 是他女儿
age 16, the daughter.
男的裹尸装回来 女的要留活口
We bag-and-tag the male. We apprehend the female.
警察
情报更新
Intel update.
归援高中今天有舞会 傍晚六点
Baktan High School dance today, 1800.
九到十二年级参加
Grades nine through 12.
注意 注意 全体注意 呼叫幺三
Break, break, break, net call one-three.
我们分组行动
We're gonna split the team.
一组去学校
Cell One to the high school.
二组随我去目标住处
Cell Two to the residence with me.
警察
各位下午好 我是特工托杰姆
Good evening, gentlemen. Special Agent Toejam.
今晚的主要目标 是霍氏香香鸡速冻食品厂
Our main target tonight is Rimhorn's Chicken Lickin' Frozen Food Farm.
情报显示 香香鸡厂只是幌子
HUMINT reporting has led us to believe Chicken Lickin' is a front
实际上 它是这一带的 大规模海洛因分销点
for a large-scale heroin distribution operation within the AO.
边境战术应对小组 你们的任务是
BTR, your main effort, you are tasked with the clearing and securing
搜查并控制香香鸡速冻食品厂
of Chicken Lickin' Frozen Food Farm in order to destroy
以捣毁该区域内的海洛因分销窝点
heroin distribution operations within the AO.
同时当地警方也会行动
Simultaneously, local law enforcement,
你们负责搜查并控制布拉茨基轮胎行
You will clear and secure Blatski's Tires,
老加州大街上的拉里贝托墨西哥餐厅
Raliberto's Mexican Restaurant on Old California Road,
归援商场里的巨鲨墨西哥夹饼店
Tiburón's Taco Shack in the Baktan Mall,
还有杰及工业大街上的加油站
and the gas station on J and Boiler Street.
这是个庇护城市
This is a sanctuary city
有几千拉丁裔
for thousands of wet bodies.
当地的居民很可能
Expect the local populace to be
会同情 甚至包庇
sympathetic and supportive
我们今晚要突击的犯罪组织
to the criminal organizations we are targeting tonight, gentlemen.
多谢
Thank you.
你还没醒酒
You're hungover,
凌晨三点才回家
and you got home at 3:00 in the morning.
你去哪儿了？
Where were you?
去哪儿？
Where, what?
宝贝 你也不帮我热一下
This isn't even warm, sweetie.
你去哪儿了？
Where were you?
我去哪儿？
Where was I?
我去了 我...
I was...
我特地告诉过你我去了哪儿
Well, I specifically told you where I was.
你问过我 我也回答了你
You asked me that. I told you where I was.
我去了乡土酒馆 听乐队演奏
I was at the Rustic Inn with the old band.
是我们以前爱听的乐队 记得吗？
You remember our old band, right?
就是他们 正常街区外
The old band, sweetie. A Block Past Normal.
记得艾伯特吗？
You remember Albert?
记得
Yeah.
我才知道
Turns out,
艾伯特买了一些旧设备
Albert bought all this old equipment
都是史提利·丹乐队的录音室用过的
from Steely Dan's old studio
【史提利·丹乐队：1970年代美国摇滚与爵士融合乐队】
他买下这些就是为了玩复古
to try to get that sort of vintage, you know,
追求所谓的真空管音色
that sort of crackling tube sound.
现在谁要听这种东西？
You don't need any of that stuff anymore.
他还买了个电脑软件
He brought out a computer program.
说是只要按一下按钮
Boom, with the press of a button--
你怎么回家的？
How'd you get home?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你怎么回家的？
How did you get home?
我开车回来的
Well, with my car.
醉驾了？
You drove?
怎么？难道你是我的保姆吗？
So what are you, my babysitter? What, what, what...
对啊
Yeah.
我会喝酒 也会开车 我能照顾好自己
I know how to drink and drive, honey. I know what I'm doin'.
- 我也没喝那么多 - 爸爸
- I didn't have that much. - Dad.
什么？
What?
干吗？
说呀
What?
我也不想当你的保姆
I don't wanna be your babysitter.
我不想天天操心你有没有
I don't wanna worry if you wrapped
把车撞到电线杆子上
your cararound a telephone pole.
我没有撞到电线...
Well, I didn't wrap my--
我不是这个意思
I didn't ask for this.
可我怎么躺上这种事情？
That's just how the cards were rolled out for me.
不对
It's...
是摊上
It's "dice," sweetie.
什么？
What?
不是躺上这种事 是摊上这种事
It's not "cards." You don't roll cards. It's dice.
滚一边去 鲍勃
Fuck off, Bob.
别再扯这些了 好吗？
Just fuck off with that, okay?
成熟点儿
Grow up.
好吧
Wow. Okay.
我想说 你能表达自己的观点
Well, you... Look. I like the way you're standin' up for yourself.
这样非常好
I'm proud of ya, honey,
但是有时候
but the way you, uh,
你对你爸说话的方式有点...
Speak to your father sometimes, it's just...
你说得也对
I don't know. You're right.
以后多跟我坦诚相待
You should tell me what you think, always.
任何事情都不要瞒我
Never hold anything back from me.
你到底是有什么毛病？
What the fuck is wrong with you?
说得对 我得记住 我这人有毛病
You're right. That's somethin' I gotta remember.
时不时还会搞砸事情
And I fuck up sometimes.
谁来了？
Whoa. Who's this?
那是谁？
Who's that?
是什么人？
Who is that?
只是我的朋友
They're just my friends.
朋友？
And they just,
还开个红色的车
They have a red car like that, just drivin'...
太张扬了吧？
Little loud, don't you think?
一辆车而已
It's just a car.
- 是你让他们开过来的？ - 对
- And you told 'em they could do that? - Yes.
到我们家门口？
Told 'em to come to the house?
怎么了
Yes!
那个涂口红的是谁？
Now, who's the one with the lipstick?
叫什么名字？
What's that one's name?
波波
Bobo.
波波 这是男的？女的？还是别的什么性别？
Bobo. Now, is that a he or a she or a they?
行了 老爸
Dad, come on.
我只是想知道 这位是在性别过渡还是…
No, are they transitioning? I wanna know if...
人家是是非二元性别
They're nonbinary.
【非二元性别：不完全认同传统男女二元分类的性别身份】
好吧 我只是想确定一下称呼
Okay, I just wanna be polite. All right.
没什么好确定的 用中性词
It's not that hard! "They, them."
门口那个臭小子又是谁？
And who's this little fuckin' freak at the door?
大概是布罗托
Probably Bluto.
就这样登门的？
They're just comin' to my house like this, huh?
怎么了？
Yes!
没事
All right.
这小子是不是你的舞伴？
Is that your date to the dance?
- 是我朋友 - 好吧
- My friend. - Okay.
你哪儿也不许去
You're not goin' anywhere with your goddamn friend
除非拿上这个
until you take it.
快拿上
Take it!
信
任
配
对
器
对 放在口袋里
Yep. Put it in your pocket.
我不想放在口袋里
I don't wanna put it in my pocket.
那就放在吊袜带里面好了
Put it in your garter or whatever you got.
谁还穿吊袜带？
My fucking garter?
什么？你这...
What? Mother...
你有什么事？
What's up, homie?
嘿 你好吗？
Hey, how's it goin'?
你没事吧？
You cool?
没事 我就是来接薇拉
Yeah. I was just here to pick up Willa.
对 对
Yeah, yeah.
你平时敲别人家门都是这么大声吗？
You normally knock that loud at somebody's house like that?
- 是 - 耐心等着
- Uh, yeah. - Yeah, give us a sec, homie.
可以放在...你带包吗？
Put it in... You got a purse?
你必须拿上它
This is non-negotiable!
放在你包里
Put it in your purse!
没人会来抓你的 鲍勃
Nobody's coming to get you, Bob.
你自己也知道
You know that, right?
那是你以为
That's what you think.
你们好吗？
What's up, guys?
都不错吧？
You guys cool?
- 你们是朋友吗？ - 是
- You guys hangin'? - Yep.
要去舞会吗？
Goin' to the dance?
好 没问题
Yeah, it's cool.
听着 记住
Listen, I'm gonna tell you somethin',
如果你敢伤害薇拉
whatever you do to her,
我就会对你以牙还牙
I'm gonna do that exact same thing
还会报复你们全家
to your entire fuckin' family.
我说真的
I'm not fuckin' around.
你说什么？
Wait, what?
爸爸
Dad?
我就是随便聊聊
I'm just tellin' ya.
我们正探讨自由呢
We're talkin' about freedom, baby.
我们在探讨自由
We're talkin' about freedom.
自由这东西真怪
Freedom's a funny thing, isn't it?
拥有的时候
When ya have it,
你并不珍惜
you... you don't appreciate it,
等到你渴望自由 它砰一下就没了
and when you miss it, it's gone.
彻底没了
It's just gone.
砰
Poof!
好吧
Okay.
烤箱里有藜麦焗烤糖霜玉米片
There's a quinoa casserole with Frosted Flakes in the oven.
别忘了
Don't leave it on.
遵命 玩得开心 小子
Got it. Have fun, homie.
谢谢
All right.
好 去吧
All right, cool.
快放开他
Let go of him.
喂
Yo!
什么？
Yeah?
跟你没关系 伙计
Not you, ese.
我在跟她说话 快上车吧
Her, I'm talkin' to her. Get in the fuckin' car.
说吧
Say it.
说那句话 亲爱的
Say it, baby.
爱你 鲍勃
Love you, Bob.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
没个正形儿
Fuckin' freaks.
谁有充电器？我手机没电了
Does anyone have a charger? My phone's dead.
没有 你裙子真好看
No. I love your skirt.
谢谢 你的也很漂亮
Thank you. I love your dress.
谢谢
Thanks.
话说你老爸也太凶了吧
Your dad's aggro, bro.
他有被害妄想
He's fuckin' paranoid, okay?
好吧
Okay.
看那边
This is...
♪ 教练打电话给年轻的谢克·韦斯
♪ Callin' a young Sheck Wes' phone ♪
♪ 阿里怎么还不把钱拿来 ♪
♪ Where's Ali with the motherfuckin' dough ♪
就停在网球场旁
By the tennis court.
等等 谁手上有视频？
Wait, who got that video?
然后 最精彩的还没讲呢
And...no. That's not even the best part.
- 然后 她直接就吐在车上了 - 借过
- And she literally threw up on it. - Oops. Sorry.
- 什么？ - 真的
- What? - Yes!
等等 有人把这段拍下来了吗？
Wait, do you think someone out there has a video of that?
- 肯定有人录 - 真的
- Wait. I bet they do. - Wait.
快去问问汤姆和罗恩
We need to go find Tom and Ron.
亲爱的 不要害怕
Baby, don't be scared.
明白吗？我要说暗号了
All right? Now, I'm gonna say it.
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies and Hooterville Junction."
【新青入乡：指城市出身者下乡格格不入 亦可指新获绿卡或新移民 源自美剧《绿野情》】
来吧 亲爱的 回应我
Come on, baby, say it back to me.
【暴富新贵：指突得财富却格格不入的新土豪 象征阶级反转 源自美剧《贝弗利山人》】
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, Hooterville Junction."
“上层建筑再也不重要了”
"Will no longer be so goddamn relevant."
【中枢小镇：源自流行文化中的虚构城镇 象征剧情交会与相互作用的舞台】
“洗脑的肥皂剧也洗不掉她们的关切”
"And women will not care if Dick finally got down with Jane on Search for Tomorrow."
“因为黑人会走上街头”
"Because Black people will be in the streets..."
“带着未来的希冀”
"Looking for a brighter day."
“革命永远不会被喉舌转播”
"The revolution will not be televised."
我爸说如果有人对我念这段话
My dad said if anyone said that shit to me
就无条件信任对方
to trust 'em with my life.
现在你必须信任我
All right, right now, you need to.
因为你有麻烦了 薇拉
'Cause you're in trouble, Willa.
明白吗？有人发了求救信号
All right? Now, there's an SOS signal out.
我是来帮你的
I am here to help.
但我们得马上离开这儿
But we have to leave here right away.
听着 我认识你妈妈
Look, I knew your mom
还有你爸爸
and your dad.
你一定有很多问题 我会回答的
I know you have a lot of questions, and I'll answer 'em later,
但现在我们得快走
but right now, we have to roll.
你愿意跟我走吗？
Will you leave here with me?
去哪儿？
Where?
只要不是这儿
Anywhere but here.
好
'Kay.
好的
Okay.
你必须待在我身边
You have to stay by my side,
严格执行我说的话 明白了吗？
and you have to do exactly as I say. Do you understand?
是 长官
Yes, ma'am.
你带手机了吗？
Do you have a phone on you?
没有
No.
很好
All right.
走吧 亲爱的
Come on, baby, let's go.
♪ 不许回头
♪ Oh don't you dare look back ♪
♪ 眼睛看着我
♪ Just keep your eyes on me ♪
♪ 我说你在犹豫
♪ I said, "You're holding back" ♪
♪ 她说闭嘴 和我跳舞吧 ♪
♪ She said "Shut up and dance with me" ♪
那我爸怎么办？
Wait, what about my dad?
不用担心他 他受过训练
He'll know what to do. He trained for this.
我的天啊 快点儿
Oh, God. Come on.
快 使劲儿跑
Come on, baby, come on!
走 走 走 走
Go, go, go, go, go!
幺三戊 幺三戊 开灯 关音乐
One-Three-Echo, One-Three-Delta. Lights, music.
♪ 这个女人是我的命中注定 她说道 ♪
♪ This woman is my destiny she said... ♪
你跟他们说 都站到场地中间
Have you get all these kids in the center of the gym.
告诉他们不要惊慌
Tell 'em everything's gonna be okay.
警察
都安静一下 我要说几句话
I need to get 'em set down, and I gotta talk to 'em.
大家听着
Everybody, listen!
所有人都站起来 站在球场中央
I need you guys to stand up and join everybody else on the court.
（法语）“还要为使我们同胞染上恶习负责”
《阿尔及尔之战》
【《阿尔及尔之战》（1966）：再现阿尔及利亚争取独立的反殖民斗争】
- 认识薇拉·弗格森吗？ - 不认识
- Do you know Willa Ferguson? - No.
- 七八九十 - 认识薇拉·弗格森吗？
- Seven eight nine ten. - Do you know Willa Ferguson?
- 你们来排队 - 不认识
- Let's get in line. - No.
认识薇拉·弗格森吗？
Do you know Willa Ferguson?
“只有那时
"Only then
才能战胜真正的敌人”
can we take on our real enemy."
“全民解放阵线”
"National Liberation Army."
（法语）“第二十四号公报”
（法语）“阿尔及利亚人民殖民地政府...”
喂？
Yeah?
鲍勃
Bob?
是哪位？
Who's this?
“我们有麻烦了 路上不太平”
"We have trouble ahead. And the road isn't clear."
你说什么？
Wait, excuse me?
你 你是哪位？
Who is this?
- 你是谁？ - 请你背诵暗号
- Who is this? - I need the greeting code, Bob.
完蛋
Oh, fuck.
我已经不记得暗号是什么
Well, I don't remember the fuckin' greeting code
因为我有点嗨
because I got a little bit high.
那个 已经好多年了
And I... it's been fuckin' years,
你能不能提示我一下？
so you gotta help me out here with this.
我不太 那个
I don't...
你得自己想
You're gonna have to think.
也对
Right.
好
Hm. Okay. "The..."
“太阳 太阳...”
"The sun, the sun..."
好好想
Think.
太阳 是“日出 日出”
"The sunrise. Sunrise,
“日出在西方”对吗？
sunrise in the west." Right?
哎
Ah.
校园被突袭了
The campus has been raided
他们带走了倔山羊
and the Billy Goat has been taken.
倔山羊就是萨默威尔
Billy Goat is Howard Sommerville,
所以霍华德·萨默威尔被带走了
so Howard Sommerville has been taken.
也许还被干掉了
He's been taken or killed.
到底是怎么回事？
What's goin' on?
被带走了 昨天的事
Taken. Yesterday.
现在情况更糟
And it gets worse.
“铁锤出动了 来到了归援十字市”
"The Hammer is loose and en route to Baktan Cross."
你是说 史蒂文...
Steve Lock...
那个史蒂夫·勒喉乔出动了吗？
Steve fucking Lockjaw?
怎么会闹成这个样子？搞什么？
What in the motherfucking fuck?
情况还能更糟吗？
How could it get any fuckin' worse than that?
- 史蒂夫·勒喉乔 什么？ - 你要保持高度警惕
- You're saying Steve Lockjaw... -It's high alert, Bob.
一切都不安全 一切都不对劲
Nothing is secure. Everything is wrong.
任何人都不能信任
No one is above suspicion.
不不不 慢一点儿 好吗？
No, no, no. Slow down. Okay?
我女儿
My daughter...
我女儿现在不在家里
my fuckin' daughter left the house.
她没有和我在一起
She's not in the house with me,
你得多告诉我一些信息
so you gotta give me more information.
薇拉很安全
Willa's secure.
香槟女士的小队已经把薇拉接走了
Lady Champagne and her team have extracted Willa.
- 她很安全 - 好
- She's safe. - Good.
很好 就让她待在那儿
Okay, good. Keep her there.
集合地点还是和之前一样
The rendezvous points are the same as they've ever been.
到时候见
We'll be seeing you.
到时候 等等 集合地点在哪儿？
I'll be seeing... Well, okay. Tell me the rendezvous point.
到底是…
What's the...
喂？
Hello?
你们要在哪儿集合？喂？
What's the fuckin' rendezvous... Hello?
可恶
Fuck!
糟了
Fuck.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 鲍勃
Okay, Bob.
先冷静
Don't panic.
不要慌 鲍勃
Don't fuckin' panic, Bob.
不要乱了阵脚
Keep your shit together.
你要保持理智
Don't get fuckin' paranoid, man.
镇定 镇定 想想该怎么办
Don't get fuckin' paranoid. Do what you gotta do.
好的 第一步先做什么？
Okay, step one, step one, step one.
进右手门
Open doorway, right.
初步排查完成 正在进一步检查
Initial clearance complete. Conducting back clear.
安全
Clear.
检查厨房 还有客厅 你去后面
Kitchen. Living room. Get the back.
发现地道
I got a tunnel!
地道？
Tunnel!
真见鬼 你怎么看？
God damn it. What do you think?
他是个炸弹狂人
He's a bomber.
拿瓦斯
Gas.
盖上
Cover.
不 糟了
No, no!
呛死了
Oh, God!
勇气 敬意 荣誉
瑟吉奥·圣卡洛斯忍者学院 加州归援十字市
（保健品大促销）
快点 快点 快接
Come on, come on.
“日上三竿”
"Rise and shine."
对
Okay...
“眨眼之间”
"Bat an eyelash."
“早上好”
"Good morning."
“钟上没有指针”
"There are no hands on the clock."
“怎么回事？”
"Why?"
“因为没有必要”
"Because they're not needed."
“那现在是几点？”
"What time is it?"
见鬼
Ah, fuck.
好吧 说实话
You know,
我不太记得这段了
I don't remember that part, all right?
一个暗号而已 拜托别太严格
Let's just not nitpick over the password stuff.
我就是鲍勃·弗格森
Look, this is Bob Ferguson, all right?
你们刚给我来过电话
You just called my house.
就别对暗号了
Let's cut the shit.
我要知道集合地点
I need the rendezvous point.
“那现在是几点？”
"What time is it?"
听着 史蒂文·勒喉乔闯进了我家
Look, Steve Lockjaw just attacked my home.
我女儿也不在我身边
I lost my daughter.
- 我是鲍勃·弗格森 你明白吗？ - 嗯
- This is Bob Ferguson. Do you understand?  -Right. Yes.
我真的不记得什么暗…
I don't remember any more of this...
我想不起来暗号是什么了 好吗？
I don't remember any more of this code speak, all right?
说正事吧 集合地点在哪儿？
Let's just get on with it. What is the rendezvous point?
可以 但你要告诉我现在是几点
Okay, I need you to give me the time.
死脑筋是吧 耍我是吧？
You motherfucker. You fuckin' with me?
你觉得这样很好玩吗？
Are you fuckin' with me, motherfucker?
你们刚找过我
You just called me.
我是鲍勃·弗格森 听见了吗？
This is Bob Ferguson. You understand that?
抵抗组织或者法式七五的人
Somebody from the resistance or the French 75
刚给我打过电话 就刚才
just called my house. Just now!
“那现在是几点？”是接头的关键问题
"What time is it" is a key question of the underground movement, okay?
记住暗号和代码非常重要
Studying the texts is essential.
可是我真的不记得这套暗号了
I don't remember any more of this code speak.
我只记得一半
I only remember half of this shit,
凑巧记住了这个电话号码 简直是奇迹
and this stupid fuckin' hotline, which is a fuckin' miracle.
所以别再胡扯了
So stop fuckin' with me
快点儿把集合地点告诉我
and give me the fuckin' rendezvous point.
你当初学暗号手册时应该认真一点儿
Well, maybe you should have studied the rebellion text a little harder.
不 是你们找的我
No, no, you called me.
- 听懂了没有？你个白痴 - 先生
- Do you understand that, you fuckin' retard? - Sir...
是你们找我
You called me!
我要去见我女儿
I need to find my daughter.
等确定了是几点 再来电话吧
Well, then call us back when you have the time.
什么？你…
Did you, you just...
居然敢挂我电话
Did you just fuckin' hang up on me,
自由派的大混蛋
you fuckin' liberal fuckin' prick?
可恶
You...
（西班牙语）- 警察 - 警察
（警察 边境战术应对小组）
（西班牙语）- 都出去 - 排队走 快点
快点
Okay, let's go!
快走快走 所有人都走
Let's go, let's go, everybody, let's go!
干什么呢？
What are you doin'?
举起手 跪下去 跪下去
Hands up, on your knees! On your knees!
举起手来 跪在地上
Get your hands up! Police! Turn around!
蕾娜
Reina.
（西班牙语）嗨 瑟吉奥 你在哪儿？
我在工作
I'm at work.
（西班牙语）你听到消息了吗？
什么消息？
With what?
（西班牙语）移民局的人来了
（西班牙语）把香香鸡厂的人都带走了
（西班牙语）我看下一个就是我们
为什么这样说？
Why do you say that?
（西班牙语）因为西尔维娅刚给我打电话
（西班牙语）说是马科斯告诉她的
（西班牙语）他们把轮胎店和加油站的人 也全带走了
你等一下
Hang on a sec.
你有什么事吗？
Yeah, can I help you?
是我鲍勃
Bob.
鲍勃·弗格森 是你
Bob. Ferguson, yeah.
- 你还好吗？ - 帮帮我 大师
- You okay? - I need your help, Sensei.
- 好 - 你一定要帮我
- Okay. - I need your help, man.
你还在吗？
You still there?
敬意
- （西班牙语）在 - 你几点下班？
What time do you get off work?
（西班牙语）一点下班
（西班牙语）你什么时候到家？
很快就到 跟玛丽塞拉说一声
I'm coming. Call Marisela and tell her I'm on my way.
（西班牙语）你在哪儿？
我就快上车了
I'm basically in the car.
（西班牙语）所有人都要转移是吗
对
Yes.
我先给埃斯佩兰萨打个电话
I'm gonna call Esperanza,
再给你回电 好吗？
and I'll call you back, okay?
好 再见
Okay. Bye.
（西班牙语）好吧 拜拜
鲍勃 该走了
Bob! We gotta go.
敬意
我需要武器
I need a weapon, man!
你这儿只有一堆没用的双节棍
All you got is goddamn nunchucks here!
你知道哪儿有枪吗？
You know where I can get a gun?
糟了
Shit.
又来了 可恶
Shit. God damn it. Shit.
出什么事了？
Bob, what's going on?
是人类联盟 他们的人到处都是
It's MKU. MKU, man, they're everywhere right now!
- 躲都躲不开 - 人类联盟什么？
- They're everywhere. - MKU? MKU what?
他们炸开了我家大门
They busted open my door.
还到处找我和薇拉 就现在
They're comin' after me and Willa right now. Right now.
那可真够受的
That's heavy metal, bro.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿 薇拉在哪儿？
Hey. Where is she?
不知道 我得先给这个手机充电
I don't know. I gotta charge my phone to find out.
用我的手机
Here, use my phone.
不行 会被追踪的
I can't, I can't. They'll trace that phone.
我得用这个手机
I gotta use my phone.
去我家弄吧 我们得走了
Let's do that at my place, huh? We gotta go.
你家？
Your place?
对
Yeah.
你家里有枪吗？
You got a gun at your place?
我给你找一把
I'll get you a gun.
- 你有枪 对吗？ - 好吗？对
- You have a gun, right? - Okay? Yes.
好吧
Okay.
他们现在要来个一网打尽
Right now, it's a goddamn roundup.
我得做点什么
I gotta deal with this shit.
好的 对 我们
Okay. Yeah, let's, let's...
我们 把手机带好
Let's take that to go. Come on.
- 我们去你家 - 走吧
- Let's go to your place. - Come on.
去你家
Let's go to your place.
充电 拿枪
I'll charge my phone. You got a gun there.
鲍勃 鲍勃 先等一下
Bob, Bob, Bob.
什么？干什么？
What? What?
别绷得这么紧 好吗？
Get off the tatami.
- 好吗？ - 好的
- Okay. Yeah.
好的 听我的
Okay. Listen.
深呼吸
Breathe.
好
All right.
好吗？冷静
Okay? Cool out.
心如止水 平静 平静
Ocean waves. Ocean waves.
心如止水
Ocean waves.
走吧 我们走
Let's go. Let's go.
我陪着你呢 来吧
I'll follow you. Come on.
（西班牙语）老天保佑你 埃斯佩兰萨
（西班牙语）地下室的门开着
（西班牙语）我二十分钟后到
我家就像是个拉丁裔的“地下铁路”
Got a little Latino Harriet Tubman situation going on at my place.
【哈莉特·塔布曼与地下铁路：女性废奴领袖 领导“地下铁路”助数百人逃离奴役】
发自内心的自愿帮助
All legit, from the heart.
不收钱
No cash.
用我的手机
Here, use my phone.
不不 不行
No, no. No, no, man,
会被追踪的 懂吗？
they trace that.You understand?
通话会被监听
They trace those calls.
干吗戴墨镜？
What's with the shades?
见鬼
Fuck.
听着 我和薇拉她妈妈
Look, me and Willa's mom,
过去我们很不安分 到处闹事
We used to run around and do some real bad shit together, all right?
我们是法式七五的成员
We were part of the French 75.
她妈妈以前被抓了 现在又来抓我们
They got her, now they're comin' after us.
真见鬼
Fuck.
那你够坏的啊 鲍勃
You're a bad hombre, Bob.
坐下
Sit down.
（人类联盟野战行动 边境战术应对小组）
我是丹佛斯特工 你好吗？
I'm Agent Danvers. How are you?
很好
Great.
好 你叫什么？
Great. What's your name?
布罗托
Bluto.
布罗托 很高兴认识你
Bluto. Nice to meet you, Bluto.
能看下你的手机吗？请你解锁一下
Do ya mind if I have your phone? Go ahead and unlock it for me.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿 抱歉闯进了你们的派对
Hey, sorry for crashin' the party like we did
但我们有几个问题想问你
but we have a few questions we wanna ask ya.
你愿意回答吗？
Is that all right with you?
可以
Sure.
你在发抖 还好吗？
You're shakin'. Are you okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
你紧张了？
You nervous?
有一点
Little bit.
需要什么吗？
Do you need anything?
不用了
No, we're good.
只要你说实话
If you tell me the truth,
马上就可以离开这儿
You're outta here in ten seconds.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
你要是撒谎 就会有麻烦
If you lie to me, we're gonna have some problems.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
- 你认识薇拉·弗格森吧？ - 认识
- You know Willa Ferguson, right? - I do.
关系怎么样？
How do you know her?
我们是好朋友
We're good friends.
好的 你知道她在哪儿吗？
Okay. Do you know where she is right now?
不太清楚
I'm not sure.
最后一次见到她是什么时候？
When's the last time you saw her?
在学校舞会上
I saw her at the dance.
在你们闯进来之前
Before you guys came in to the dance.
她手机号多少？
What's her number?
她没有手机
She doesn't have a phone.
她爸不让她用手机
Her dad doesn't let her, so...
我看全美国的高中生
The only high school girl in America,
也就她薇拉·弗格森没有手机了
Willa Ferguson, doesn't have a phone.
差不多吧
I guess so.
二小队 告诉我瑟吉奥·圣卡洛斯的住址
Alpha Two, I need a residential address for a Sergio St. Carlos.
那是什么？
What is it?
老的追踪配对器
It's an old tracking device.
能用的话只要两个足够近 就会开始放旋律
It goes off when it's within 100 yards of hers, if it works.
就没怎么能用过
And it never works.
有时候确实管用 但基本都不行
Sometimes it does, but mostly it doesn't.
要不打她手机？
What about her phone?
她没有手机
She doesn't have a phone.
难道她有手机吗？
What, she has a phone?
对啊
Yes.
可她 你有她手机号吗？
She's on... You have her phone number, man?
没有
No.
不过大家都知道她有手机
Everybody knows she has a phone, though.
大家都知道她…
Everybody knows she has a...
那她为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't she tell me she has a phone?
也许她不想惹你生气
Maybe she didn't want you to get mad.
她就不该有手机
She's not allowed to have a goddamn phone!
她可能就是怕你生气嘛
Well, maybe she didn't want you to get mad.
我不生气 我现在什么事都不生气了
I don't get mad. I don't get mad about anything anymore.
害怕吗？
Scared?
不怕
No.
是吗？
No?
你应该害怕
Well, you should be.
你爸提过史蒂文·勒喉乔这个人吗？
Your dad ever mention Steve Lockjaw?
提过
Yeah.
是吗？他怎么说的？
Yeah? What'd he tell you?
就是他杀了我妈妈
He's the one who killed my mom.
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
上强硬手段 以火制火
Let's fight fire with fire.
遵命
Roger that.
全体注意 火爆吉他手出动
Net call, send in Eddie Van Halen.
【埃迪·范海伦：极具能力的吉他手 此处指具有特殊能力的人员】
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
全体就位
Personnel ready!
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
放催泪瓦斯
Gas, gas, gas!
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
前进 快
Forward, move!
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
真是倒霉
Oh, my God.
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
比吉
BeeGee!
（西班牙语）晚上好啊 大师
什么情况？
What's the word?
别提了 三战爆发都没这么热闹
It's fuckin' World War III out there, yo!
（西班牙语）前面乱成一锅粥了
马上到新源杂货集合
Meet me at Genesis, right now.
（西班牙语）没问题 大师
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
这都是我的人 懂了吗？
They're with me. Okay?
帮他把东西搬进去
Help him bring everything inside,
搬完上楼找我
then meet me upstairs.
别被锁外面
Don't get locked out!
（西班牙语）- 你好 我想知道插座在哪儿 - 在那边
喂 都听好 这里关门了
Oh! Everybody. The store is closed.
去帮忙 快点去
Help! Go help. Come on.
充电的地方在哪儿？
You got a charger, homie?
- 都去搭把手 - 谢谢
- Let's go, give a hand. - Thank you.
- 关门了 - 你会说英语
- Come on. We're closing. - You speak English!
谢谢你 哥们
Thank you, bro.
是
Hey.
得在20分钟内把大家送去教堂
We got 20 minutes to get everybody to the church.
- 明白吗？ - 明白
- Okay? - Okay.
- 我需要你帮忙 你要到楼上去 - 好的
- I need your help. Okay? I need you to go upstairs - Okay.
帮我做件事儿
and do me a favor.
你害怕走地道 所以我带你走
I know you don't like the tunnel. You're gonna have to come with me.
- 好 - 上楼去帮他们吧
- Okay. Okay. - Go upstairs, give 'em a hand. Yeah.
埃斯特班 别玩手机了
Esteban! Esteban, get off your phone. Ándale.
快到大门口去 帮忙盯着点儿
Come to the front of the store and keep an eye on the store.
（西班牙语）埃斯特班 快去
别玩手机了
Hey, get off the phone!
别玩手机了 快去
Get off the phone! Come on!
我哪有玩手机 哥们？
I'm not on the phone, man!
真烦人
God damn!
- 我是想给手机充电 懂了吗？ - 拿到楼上去充
- I'm trying to charge the phone! You see that? - Bring it upstairs.
- 充个电真麻烦 - 到楼上去充
- Goddamn, man! - Bring it upstairs.
（西班牙语）家人们 家人们
（西班牙语）听我说 赶紧带上孩子 排成一队
（西班牙语）移民局的人就要来了 我们得走了
（西班牙语）快点 快点
（西班牙语）都站成一排 不用担心 不会有事的
（西班牙语）大家都听我说 都不用害怕
（西班牙语）老天会保佑我们的 大家都不会有事
（西班牙语）但我们要赶快离开
东西全都拿走 别留下痕迹
Guys, clean it up. Spick-and-span.
鲍勃 这儿不安全 跟我来
Bob. Not safe for you there. Follow me.
（西班牙语）快点 孩子们 快走
德瑞克 让他们在走廊排好队
Derrick, line 'em up in the hallway!
我去24号房
I'll be in 24!
（西班牙语）没问题 哥们
俗话说得好 有得必有失 鲍勃
You win some and you lose some, Bob.
是啊
Yeah.
鲍勃 这儿
Bob, Bob, Bob.
你冷静一点儿
Get back on defense.
冷静 没问题
Back on defense, man, yeah.
好
Yeah.
谢谢兄弟 太谢谢了
Thank you, man. Thank you, thank you.
在这儿
Here.
到我屋里去 更隐蔽
Do it in my room. It's more privacy.
奥布里 别玩手机了
Aubrey, get off the phones.
赶快到二楼去
Go to the second floor.
要转移阵地 别玩了
We're moving them out.
你房间在那儿是吗？
Where's your room? Back here, man?
- 对了 鲍勃 - 什么？
- Hey, Bob, Bob. - Yeah?
- 认识一下大家 - 好
- This is everybody. - Yeah. Hi.
- 大家认识一下鲍勃 - 嗨
- Everybody, this is Bob. - Hi.
你好 鲍勃
Hello, Bob.
他是白人版萨帕塔
The Gringo Zapata.
【利亚诺·萨帕塔：墨西哥革命领袖】
都打个招呼
Everyone, say hello.
（西班牙语）很好 你好吗 哥们？
（西班牙语）不要认输
雅各布 你赶快到二楼去
Jacob, I need you to go to the second floor.
玛丽塞拉 要带他们走
Marisela, we're moving them out.
- 什么？ - 赶快去
- What? - Now, now.
好了 鲍勃 这是瑞秋
Yeah. Bob, Bob. Bob. This is Rachel.
- 嗨 瑞秋 你好吗？ - 这是鲍勃
- Hi, Rachel. How are you? - Rachel, this is Bob
这是兰登 最小的一个
and this is Landon, the newest one.
兰登 你好吗？
Hey, Landon. How are you?
嗨 插座在那儿是吗？
Hey, is it back there?
- 对 在这儿 - 谢谢
- Okay. Yeah. Back here. - Thank you.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
就在那个沙发后面
Right here. Right behind the couch.
谢谢你兄弟 谢谢
Thank you, brother, thank you.
玛利亚 玛迪森 出去
Mariah. Madison. Come on.
出去
Out.
别待在我屋里
Come on, it's my room.
这才是乖孩子
Thank you, girls.
好了
Yeah. Come on.
拜托 快点
Come on. Come on.
倒霉
Shit.
抱歉 兄弟
Sorry, man.
快点儿
Come on.
没事
It's okay.
求你了 快点开机
Come on, baby. Come on, baby. Come on, baby.
快点开机 快点呀 求你了
开机了 开机了
I got power. I got power.
（西班牙语）那太好了
快点
Come on.
快接 快接 快接
Please, please, please.
“日上三竿”
"Rise and shine."
嗨
Hi.
你好 你好兄弟
What's up, homie?
我又打电话了 我是鲍勃
It's me again. Bob Ferguson.
还记得吗？
I don't know if you remember,
我刚才给你打过电话
but we spoke earlier on the phone.
咱俩也许有点小误会
I think we had a little misunderstanding.
也许你对我印象不好
I think we got off on the wrong foot.
我只是想知道集合地点
I was trying to get the rendezvous point
- 我想见我女儿 薇拉 - 好吧
- for my daughter. Willa. - Right.
你回答不出“那现在是几点？”
If you can't answer "What time is it?"
我就不能告诉你集合地点
I cannot give you the rendezvous point.
- 这是暗号手册的重要内容 - 几点啊
- This is a key tenet of the rebellion text. - "What time is it?"
你怎么会回答不上来？
I'm surprised you can't name it.
抱歉 我怀疑你根本不是鲍勃
I don't know if you are...who you say you are.
好吧 要不这样好了
Well, look, look, maybe I can...
我给你一些信息
Maybe I can give you some information
你也给我一些信息 怎么样？
and then you give me some information, all right?
互相交换信息
We'll just share a little bit of information.
我是鲍勃·弗格森
My name is Bob Ferguson.
不知道你是否听说过我
I don't know if you've ever heard of me, all right ?
我过去是法式七五的成员
I was a part of French 75 for years.
干过很多年
Years and years, all right?
大家叫我“穷鬼帕特”
They used to call me "Ghetto Pat,"
“火箭男”之类的
"Rocket Man," something like that.
唯一的问题是
Only problem is, I, uh...
如今 我的脑子不太好使
I fried my brain since then, man.
这三十年来我一直嗑药酗酒
I have abused drugs and alcohol
已经把脑子喝坏了
for the past 30 years, man.
我是个无药可救的酒鬼
I'm a drug and alcohol lover
我只知道 现在我有危险
and I cannot remember for the life of me,
我唯一的女儿也有危险
or the life of my only child,
可我无论如何也想不起来“那现在是几点？”
the answer to your question, "What time is it?"
八点十五
8:15.
听着 我得知道集合地点
Now, I need this rendezvous point,
你懂我的意思吗？告诉我吧
you understand what I'm sayin'? I need it.
我懂你的意思 但你要告诉我
I understand. And the question is...
- 去死吧 - “那现在是几点？”
- Fuck! - ..."What time is it?"
你要是不告诉我集合地点
If you don't give me the rendezvous point,
你就等着瞧吧 我一定会揪出你
I swear to God, I will hunt you down
在你五脏六腑里面塞满炸弹
and stick a loaded fuckin' hot piece of dynamite
让你死无葬身之地
right up your fuckin' asshole.
好吧 你这话越界了
Okay, this doesn't feel safe.
侵犯了我的个人空间
You're violating my space right now.
侵犯你的个人空间？
Violating your space? Man, come on,
兄弟 你算什么反抗斗士？
what kind of revolutionary are you, brother?
我们都不在一个房间
We're not even in the same room here.
- 打个电话就侵犯空间了 - 瑞秋 带孩子出去
- We're talkin' on the phone, like men! - Rachel, let's take the boys outside...
- 你没必要大吼大叫 - 去其他屋
- Okay, there's no need to shout. - ...to the other room.
你在威胁我的生命安全
This is a violation of my safety.
我感觉很不舒服
These are noise triggers.
去你的不舒服 听着
Fuckin' noise triggers. Listen,
我有个问题
I wanna know somethin'.
先不说别的 我只想知道一件事儿
I wanna know one thing when this is all said and done.
你叫什么？我想知道你叫什么
What is your name? I need to know your name.
好吧 我叫…
My name is...
乔希同志
Comrade Josh.
好 乔希同志
Yeah. Comrade Josh.
我劝你换一个名字
Well, get a better name, Comrade Josh.
哪有干革命的现在叫这种名字 太可笑了
That's a fuckin' ridiculous name for a revolutionary, first off.
另外
Second off,
你现在在哪儿？
I wanna know your coordinates.
我要知道你的坐标
I wanna know your location right now.
告诉我
What is it?
我在一个很安全的地方
I'm in a secure location, somewhere between
比东海岸要靠西
the stolen land of the Wabanaki
【瓦巴纳基与丘马什：北美原住民部族 其领土在殖民扩张中被夺走】
比西海岸要靠东 你猜吧
and the stolen land of the Chumash.
你真是太会恶心人了
You're fuckin' intolerable, man. You are...
【瓦巴纳基：传统领地在今美国东北部与加拿大东部】
你真是把我恶心坏了
You really know... you're really intolerable, man.
革命者不应该是这种德行
This is not the way the revolutionaries do shit.
【丘马什：传统领地在今美国加州南部沿海】
你一点儿道理都不讲
You know how hard you are to talk to?
我也要告诉你一句话 知道是什么吗？
Do you know the information that I'm trying to give you?
你就是个爱找茬的混蛋
You're a little nitpicking prick!
没错 你就知道找茬
That's what you are, a little nitpicking prick.
知道我会怎么对付你这种人吗？
And you know what I'm gonna do to nitpicking pricks?
我要召唤灰鹰十号
I'm gonna call in a Greyhawk Ten.
- 你要召唤灰鹰十号？ - 没错 灰鹰十号
- You're calling in a Greyhawk Ten? - I'm callin' in a Greyhawk Ten.
明白吗？
All right?
立马让你的上级接电话
I want you to get your supervisor on the phone right now,
我知道你有上级
'cause I know you got one.
同志 我要找你的上级聊聊 懂了吗？
I know you got one, Comrade Josh. All right?
我要直接越过你这个死脑筋
Yeah, I'm goin' way over your fuckin' head.
跟你的上级聊
Way over your head.
懂吗？
All right?
马上让你的指挥官接电话
Put your commanding officer on the phone now.
因为你要召唤灰鹰十号
Because you're calling in a Greyhawk Ten?
我要召唤
I'm callin' in
灰鹰十号 乔希同志
a Greyhawk Ten, Comrade Josh.
请稍等
Please hold.
死混蛋 没辙了吧
Fuckin' prick. I got him.
总算能治治他了
I got him right where I want him.
这个混蛋听着就很烦人 鲍勃
That's some fucked-up, nitpickin' shit, Bob.
拿着鸡毛当令箭
He got you on one password.
真恶心
Assholes.
抱歉兄弟
I'm sorry about...
我把这些烂事儿带到了这里
I brought all this shit to your door, man.
给你们添麻烦了
I'm sorry about everything.
（西班牙语）振作起来 鲍勃
我们已经被围攻几百年了
We've been laid siege for hundreds of years.
【几百年：一些地区并入美国后 当地原住民与墨裔长期被排斥】
你没做错什么
You did nothing wrong.
别太自责
Don't get selfish.
生活啊 真是的
Life, man.
真难
Life!
总有些破事儿 让你不得安生
Just always some little... little, tiny detail, right?
（西班牙语）都准备好了 表哥
行了 到门口去
Okay. Get to the front.
雅各布
Jacob!
要走了
We go!
好啦
Okay, guys.
（西班牙语）有秩序地撤离
（西班牙语）走慢一点
（西班牙语）当心一点 我们快走
（西班牙语）晚上好
（西班牙语）我们马上要出发了 好了兄弟 该走了
（西班牙语）很好 非常好
♪ ...在镜头前亮相 ♪
♪ ...saving for just the proper occasion ♪
【歌曲：描述黑人遭受的
压迫和不公 完整版及注释可在
片尾02：37：02欣赏】
♪ 新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇 ♪
♪ Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies and Hooterville Junction ♪
♪ 上层建筑再也不重要了 ♪
♪ Will no longer be so damn relevant ♪
这也太慢了吧
Why is this takin' so long? For God's sakes.
♪ 洗脑的肥皂剧
♪ And women will not care if Dick finally got down with Jane ♪
你这群人到底行不行啊
You guys are so incompetent. For...
♪ 也洗不掉她们的关切 ♪
♪ On Search for tomorrow ♪
可恶 效率低下 快点啊
Fuck! Hurry up.
♪ 因为黑人会走上街头 ♪
♪ Because Black people will be in the street ♪
♪ 带着未来的希冀 ♪
♪ Looking for a brighter day ♪
♪ 革命永远不会... ♪
♪ The revolution will... ♪
一小队 这是祖鲁
Alpha One, this is Zulu.
目标建筑内有人逃跑
I got a squirter internal to the target building.
追踪瑟吉奥·圣卡洛斯任务需升级行动
Follow on for Sergio St. Carlos.
准备使用武力
I need to go kinetic.
准备进行强攻
Setting up breach time now.
开来两辆支援车辆
I need two follow-on vehicles.
喂？是哪位？
Yep. Who's this?
喂？嗨 是哪位？
Yeah! Hi! Who's this?
哪位？
Who's this?
- 你是哪位？ - 你是哪位？
- Who's this? - Who's this?
我是鲍勃·弗格森 你是谁？
This is Bob Ferguson. Who's this?
好兄弟
My brother.
你是谁？
Who's this?
你哥们塔列朗
It's your man, Talleyrand.
塔列 我的好兄弟
Talley! Talley, my brother.
兄弟 听我说 我需要你的帮助
My brother, you listen, man. You gotta help me out, man.
薇拉被带走了
They got Willa.
你也知道这事儿吧
You heard they got Willa, right? I need...
我需要马上知道集合地点
I need the rendezvous point, now.
好 你需要回答一个问题 帕特
I need you to answer one question for me, Pat.
不 不行
No, no, man.
求你别再搞这套了
Please don't make me go through this, man.
- 我已经忘记答案了 - 帕特 冷静 问题很简单
- I don't remember any more of these answers - Pat. Pat. Slow down. You're gonna know it
- 过去太多年了 求你别问了 - 你知道答案
- It's been too many years. Please... - You're gonna know it.
我最喜欢哪种美女？
What's my favorite kind of pussy?
墨西哥靓女 下面剃了毛的
Mexican Hairless.
好 等一下
Okay. One second.
你这个蠢货 他可是大英雄
You motherfucker. This is a goddamn war hero.
集合地点是勇敢海狸修女会
Hey, rendezvous is Sisters of the Brave Beaver.
【海狸：象征勤奋与共同营造家园】
【海狸：在英语俚语中亦为女性生殖器的俗称 借用污名化词汇以自我赋权并挑衅权威】
勇敢海狸修女会
Sisters of the Brave Beaver. I don't know...
是山上的那个吗？
Is that that compound out in the hills?
你得告诉我准确的位置
I need the coordinates, exact coordinates.
好 等一下
Okay, one second.
帮他指路
Tell him how to get there.
还要道歉 懂吗？
Apologize. Mean it.
喂？
Hello.
嗨 混蛋 快点告诉我准确位置
Hi, prick! Give me the fuckin' coordinates now.
好的
Okay.
- 不要磨蹭 - 好的
- Make it snappy! - Okay.
那个修女会
Sister Rochelle's
- 就在旧传教路.... - 旧传教路
- is located up Old Mission Road... - Old Mission.
- 行了 慢点儿 说清楚点儿 - 和克劳溪路
- Okay, slow down, articulate. - ...to Craw Creek Road...
新源杂货
上大家伙
Bring up the hoolie.
大师 大师
Sensei! Sensei!
（西班牙语）边境警察来了 刚破门
（西班牙语）快点 快走 别磨蹭了
（西班牙语）走的时候注意脚下
（西班牙语）老天一定会保佑我们 放心吧
（西班牙语）都快走
- 在卓柏卡布拉山 - 卓柏卡布拉山
- In the Chupacabra Hills. - Chupacabra Hills.
【卓柏卡布拉：拉美民间传说中的“吸羊怪” 象征带有污名化色彩的民俗地区】
我想跟你郑重说一声 对不起
And I just wanna formally say that I am sorry.
- 这时候你知道道歉了 - 是啊
- You wanna formally say you're sorry, huh? - Yeah.
那个问题的答案到底是什么 混蛋？
What was the fuckin' password, by the way, you fuckin' prick?
“时间还不存在 但它仍然控制着我们”
"Time doesn't exist, yet it controls us anyway."
去死吧 你个死脑筋
Fuck you, you fuckin' moron!
去死吧 你这个蠢货肯定没孩子
Fuck you! You obviously don't have kids, you fuckin' idiot!
兄弟 我知道位置了
Hey! Man, I got the coordinates.
先到旧传教路
It's Old Mission Road to Craw Creek,
再到克劳溪路 卓柏卡布拉山
and then to Chupacabra Hills.
【吉姆·克劳：美国历史上代表种族隔离与制度性歧视的代称 此处路名发音接近构成双关】
该走了 鲍勃
Time to go, Bob.
好的 走吧
Right, let's go.
我知道位置了 走吧
Let's go, I got the coordinates, man.
- 鲍勃 小心窗外 - 什么？
- Look out the window, Bob. - What?
小心点儿 窗外能看到你
Be careful. Look out the window. Be careful.
天啊 该死
Shit. Shit.
他们来了
They're here!
气死我了 真是该死 他们…
God damn it, they're... Shit. They're...
奥吉 店关门了“租客”已经都走了
O.G., the store is closed. The inquilinos are gone.
他们要是敲门 你来应付
If they knock, you know what to do.
我们怎么暴露的？
How'd they find us, man?
怎么回事？
How'd they find us?
（西班牙语）快走吧
你打了太多电话
I think you were making too many calls, man.
（西班牙语）走吧
你的信号肯定被追踪了
I think they traced your call. They must have traced your calls.
现在怎么办？
What's the plan?
- 有什么计划？ - 比吉
- What's the plan, man? - BeeGee!
有什么计划？
What's the plan?
我正想呢
I'm thinking.
- 那是我的武器吗？ - 等等
- Is that my weapon? - Hang on.
- 比吉 - 有什么计划？我们得快走
- BeeGee! Okay. - We gotta go, man.
听着 你带他到楼顶去
You're gonna take him up on the roof,
到拉帕姆巷去找我的车 这是钥匙
across to my car on Lapham's Alley. Here are my keys.
送完他记得联系我
You drop him off, you call me.
拉丁小队 走了
Latino Heat, come with me!
不行 我不跟他们走
No, no, no, man, I'm not goin' with them.
我不跟他们走 我应该跟着你
No, I'm not goin' with them! I'm supposed to go with you.
我需要你 兄弟 帮帮我 大师
I need you, brother. Please, Sensei.
求求你了
Sensei, Sensei, please!
鼓起勇气 鲍勃
Courage, Bob.
振作起来
Courage.
就这样？
That's it?
振作起来
Courage.
也对 好吧 谢谢
Yeah. Yeah. Thank you.
谢谢你 大师
Hey! Thank you, Sensei.
谢谢大师 谢谢
Thank you, Sensei! Thank you!
差点忘了
God damn it!
（西班牙语）革命万岁
（西班牙语）万岁
（警察）
这边 鲍勃
This way, Bob!
（西班牙语）来 鲍勃 把东西递给我
把东西都递给我
Pass me all your shit, man!
给
Here.
我不管你用什么办法
I don't give a shit what you do.
十秒内 你得把号码告诉我
I'm gonna need that number in the next ten seconds.
我真的不知道
I know nothing, sir.
你觉得我像你爸妈那样好糊弄吗？
Do I look like your parent?
- 是啊 - 告诉我她的号码
- Kinda. - Give me the fuckin' number
不然就站起来 把手放在背后
or stand up, put your hands behind your back.
- 我不知道她的号码 - 起来
- I don't have her phone number. - Up.
把双手放在背后
Put your hands behind your back.
铐上他 把他带走
Cuff him. Get him outta here.
我想起来了
I have it.
现在你又想起来了
You have it now?
是多少？
What is it?
有点常识也知道你没资格讨价还价 坐下吧
I thought you took AP Common Sense. Sit the fuck down.
号码是多少？
What's the number?
联系人是“凯蒂猫”
It's under "Hello Kitty."
手机给我
Give it to me.
把手机给我
Give it to me!
我刚才问你有手机吗？
I asked you if you had a phone.
你看着我的眼睛 说没有
You looked me in my face, and you lied.
我跑来这里是为了救你
I am here to save your fuckin' life.
你到底懂不懂？
Do you understand?
不准再骗我了
Don't lie to me again.
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
二小队来报
Alpha Two's on the horn!
根据手机信号 女目标正沿135号路向南行驶
The female's handset's heading south on 135.
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
（警察）
等下
Freeze.
一组 收队
Cell One, Exfil.
好了
All right.
（西班牙语）来吧 兄弟们
（西班牙语）能跑多快就跑多快
该死
Fuck.
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
（西班牙语）快点儿 鲍勃 跟上 快点儿
哎呦
Fuck.
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
（西班牙语）好了 该走了 我得带上你
（西班牙语）没事的 就这样吧
比吉
BeeGee.
大师 你朋友从屋顶上掉下去 被抓住了
Sensei, your guy fell off the roof and got arrested.
你说什么？
What the fuck happened?
他跳屋顶时撞上树 摔下去十几米
He fell 40 feet and fuckin' fell in a tree, man.
然后被电击枪打中了
Chota got him with a Taser.
我的步枪呢？
And my rifle?
在我这儿
It's with me.
好吧
Okay.
圣心教堂集合
Meet me at Sacred Heart.
（西班牙语）...我们的神在天上
【背景音：出自《圣经·诗篇》第115篇3-5节】
（西班牙语）都随自己的意旨行事
（西班牙语）他们的偶像是金的 银的
（西班牙语）是人手所造的
（因为我饿了 你们给我吃 我做客旅 你们留我住）
（西班牙语）有口却不能言 有眼却不能看
罗谢尔
Rochelle.
迪安德拉 又惹了什么麻烦？
Well, Deandra, what new mischief now?
我带来个孩子 薇拉·弗格森
I have the child Willa Ferguson.
她是叛娅·富山的女儿
This is Perfidia Beverly Hills' daughter.
我来找你 因为我们现在很危险
I'm comin' to you in an hour of need
迫切需要你的帮助
and desperation for safekeeping.
真不敢相信
Unbelievable.
我和我妈长得像吗？
Do I look just like her?
不
No.
不是很像
Not really.
不过你们性格很像
But you do on the inside.
对我们来说 你很可能是个祸害
Which makes you quite a risk around here.
你妈妈是个叛徒
The daughter of a rat
你说不定也是
is a baby rat.
我们必须小心一点
And we must be careful.
你会做饭吗？
Can you cook?
会
Yes.
我们这里有规矩 要想住在这儿
We will not allow residence to anyone
每个人都要承担责任
who cannot take responsibility for both
不能只进不出
her input and output.
放心吧 我会负责好
I can earn what I eat and secure
自己的吃喝拉撒
what I shit, if that's what you mean.
你明白就好
That's what I mean.
沃克斯修女
Sister Vox,
带小叛娅去潘乔·比利亚房
show Baby Perfidia to the Pancho Villa room.
【潘乔·比利亚：墨西哥革命领袖 领导多次武装起义并推动土地再分配】
好的
A'ight.
我介绍一下寒舍
Let me run shit down to you.
首先 毛巾都在这边
So you have the towels over here.
厕所就在那边
The bathroom is straight through there.
枕头都在那儿 看到了吗？
The pillows is right there, as you can see.
别问我无线网络密码是什么
And don't ask for the fuckin' Wi-Fi,
这儿没有无线网络
'cause we ain't got none.
好好休息吧 大小姐
Make yourself at home, Goldilocks.
她知道多少？
What does she know?
她以为她母亲是英雄
She thinks her mom was a hero.
我有点儿...
And I...
不忍心告诉她真相
I didn't have the guts to tell her the truth.
太残忍了
I couldn't.
叛娅·富山可真行
Perfidia Beverly Hills
事到如今 还在给我们添麻烦
is a problem that keeps on givin'.
这场革命不能再出第二个叛娅
This revolution doesn't need another one of her runnin' around.
本来就够难了
Shit's hard enough.
迪安德拉 你比我们都要有斗志
You got more fight in you than the rest of us, Deandra.
这些破事我早就已经受够了
I got sick of this shit a long time ago.
♪ 荣耀归于新生王 ♪
♪ Glory to the newborn king ♪
♪ 听啊 天使高声唱
♪ Hark, the herald angels sing ♪
♪ 荣耀归于新生王 ♪
♪ Glory to the newborn King ♪
♪ 平安仁慈归世界
♪ Peace on earth and mercy mild ♪
♪ 神与世人再和谐 ♪
♪ God and sinners reconciled ♪
♪ 万国齐起同欢欣
♪ Joyful, all ye nations rise ♪
- 提姆 - 爱丽丝 你最近好吗？
- Tim! - Alice, how are you, darlin'?
♪ 天上地下共唱和 ♪
♪ Join the triumph of the skies ♪
我挺好的 谢谢
Very well. Thank you.
你气色不错 饿了吗？
You look great. You hungry?
♪ 同著天军传喜讯
♪ With angelic hosts proclaim ♪
是有点儿饿 但没时间吃了
Uh, yeah, yeah. But I'm actually,
我快要迟到了
I think I'm about to be runnin' late.
♪ 圣人生在伯利恒 ♪
♪ Christ is born in Bethlehem ♪
- 这样吧 我给你做薄烤饼 - 我得赶紧过去
- Well, I can fix you some pancakes. - Better get down there.
你可以拿着路上吃
You could have 'em on your way out.
♪ 听啊 天使高声唱
♪ Hark, the herald angels sing ♪
你要做香蕉薄烤饼吗？
Are these the banana pancakes?
大家都说你做的很好吃
The famous Alice banana pancakes?
♪ 荣耀归于新生王 ♪
♪ Glory to the newborn king ♪
没错 你猜对啦
Those are the ones.
我知道他们在等你
I know they're waiting for you.
我得赶紧过去
I better get down there.
见到你很高兴 爱丽丝
It's great to see you again, Alice.
♪ 欢迎天降和平王
♪ Hail the Heav'n-born Prince of Peace ♪
我也很高兴 提姆
Oh, good to see you, Tim.
♪ 欢迎辉煌公义光 ♪
♪ Hail the Sun of Righteousness ♪
♪ 赐生命也赐光
♪ Light and life to all he brings ♪
♪ 医治世人照万方 ♪
♪ Risen with healing in his wings ♪
♪ 弃荣华甘虚己
♪ Mild he lays his glory by ♪
♪ 降生救人免死亡 ♪
♪ Born that man no more may die ♪
♪ 降生使人得高升
♪ Born to raise the sons of earth ♪
♪ 降生使人得重生 ♪
♪ Born to give them second birth ♪
♪ 听啊 天使高声唱
♪ Hark, the herald angels sing ♪
♪ 荣耀归于新生王 ♪
♪ Glory to the newborn King ♪
请进
Come in.
提姆
Tim.
共荣圣诞 向圣尼古拉敬礼
Merry Christmas. Hail Saint Nick.
【圣尼古拉：基督教圣徒 圣诞老人原型】
共荣圣诞
Merry Christmas.
- 你最近好吗？ - 挺好的
- How ya doin'? - Good, good.
好久不见
It's been too long.
是啊 终于又见面了 桑迪
Yeah, it's good to see you again, Sandy.
你认识维道尔·司空伯顿吧？
You know Virgil Throckmorton.
净化与纠偏部的
Virgil's down from Cleansing and Distortion.
共荣圣诞
Merry Christmas.
- 白厅的比尔·戴斯蒙你也认识 - 是啊
- And you know Bill Desmond from Whitehall. - Yes.
比尔 再次见面很高兴 共荣圣诞
Bill, good to see you again, and merry Christmas.
你也认识罗伊·摩尔
And of course you know Roy More.
西南军区第五舰队战地司令
Fifth Fleet Field General from the Southwest.
当然认识 早上好
Absolutely, sir. Good morning.
坐下吧
Take a seat.
所以
So...
是怎么了？
what's cookin'?
要我做什么？
How can I help?
是这样的 提姆
Well, Tim,
我们听到一个很可怕的传言
There's this troubling little rumor we've just heard.
找你过来
And we brought you in
是希望你能帮忙理清一些事
to see if you can help clear it up.
比尔会向你具体交代
I'm gonna hand you over to Bill. He'll give you the details.
- 交给你了 比尔 - 好的
- Over to you, Bill. - All right.
提姆 我就直说了
Tim, I'm gonna get right to it. Um...
我接到一份报告说
There's an unconfirmed report
史蒂文·勒喉乔上校
that Colonel Steven J. Lockjaw
其实有个混血的私生子
is the father of a mixed-race child.
混了哪个人种？
Which mix?
我真的难以启齿 但是
There's no real easy way to say this, but...
好吧
Yeah.
是黑的
It's Black.
天啊
Well, uh...
这件事如果是真的
That would be quite the revelation
那就太可怕了
if it were true.
比尔 请问这消息哪儿来的？
Bill, may I ask what your source is?
来自纯血美国白人背景审查报告
Sure. That's part of a Double Yankee White background check.
我们在电脑里找到了一些旧文件
Some old paperwork turned up in a computer file
是关于一个叫贱女姜戈的黑人罪犯
on the Black militant named Junglepussy.
15年前 她就跟一个警官讲过这件事
She told an officer this very story 15 years ago.
15年前啊
Fifteen years ago.
那些文件一直都在 我们能翻出来纯属走运
It's been there the whole time, in ancient file. Pure luck we caught it.
这个贱女在哪儿？
So where's the Pussy?
她早就死了
Oh, she's long dead.
哦 贱命一条
Oh. No more Pussy.
总之 几天前
Now, a few days ago,
勒喉乔雇佣赏金猎人
Lockjaw hired a bounty hunter
在埃尔帕索抓走了一个平民
to make a civilian extraction in El Paso.
带队的是阿威腾·魁 你认识吗？
It was led by an Avanti Q. You know him?
认识 阿威腾是个好军人
Yeah, I know Avanti. He's a good soldier.
有多好？
Not great?
很不错 可惜他不是白人
I mean, he's excellent, but he's not a native son.
这是他的肮脏小秘密
That's his dirty little secret.
他假装是半个墨西哥人 其实有印第安血统
He passes for half-Mexican, but he's actually part Comanche
还是爱斯基摩人血统
or, I don't know, Eskimo.
他很擅长追踪
He's a fantastic tracker.
光看脚印 他就知道对方口袋里有多少钱
He'll tell you how much money someone had in their pocket based on a footprint,
但他不是白人 所以不可信
but he is not homegrown, so I would not trust it.
不过 显然他有足够的本事
Yeah, well, he's apparently good enough
找到勒喉乔一直想找的人
to find what Lockjaw was lookin' for.
没错 他找到了霍华德·萨默威尔
Yeah. He found Howard Sommerville.
前法式七五成员 现在运营一个地下组织
Ex-French 75. He runs an underground railroad,
将非法移民从南方边境
bringing illegals from our southern border
带去北方的归援十字市
to Baktan Cross in the north,
把那儿变成了庇护城市
where he set up a so-called sanctuary city,
帮助毒贩和神经病在美国扎根
giving jobs and housing to drug dealers and psychopaths.
他还是一个瘾君子
He's also a reefer addict.
真的？这么说他还挺有能耐的
Really? Well, he sounds like a class act, this guy.
抓走他之后
Next thing we know,
勒喉乔上校的特遣队 进入了归援十字市
Colonel Lockjaw's mobilized his task force into Baktan Cross
对香香鸡速冻食品厂
and conducted a Class-A raid
进行了最高等级突袭
on the Chicken Lickin' Frozen Farm.
哦不 我很喜欢他们家的鸡块
Oh, no. I love their nuggets.
是吗？暂时可能买不到了
Well, this could mean a nugget shortage.
更何况 厂长也是我们俱乐部的成员
Not to mention the Chicken Lickin's owned by our fellow Christmas Adventurer,
他希望那些拉丁狗非法劳工 能快点复工
Brother Burt Rimhorn, who wants his wetbacks back to work.
接着说
Next...
他还搜查了高中 提姆
He hit the high school, Tim.
没错
Yeah.
是那所高中
The high school.
现在归援十字市已经乱成一锅粥了
And now, all hell's broken loose on the streets of Baktan Cross.
他还关闭了实时共享
And he's turned off his A-TAK's.
抱歉 我插一下嘴
I'm sorry to interrupt,
我听明白你们想说什么了
But I think I'm pickin' up what you gents are layin' down here.
这些事儿确实不寻常
This is a curious chain of events.
勒喉乔在找自己的杂种私生子
So Lockjaw's lookin' for his half-breed,
但护崽的妈妈在哪里？
but do we know where the mama bear is?
这事情可有意思了
Funny you should ask that.
母亲叛娅·富山
Perfidia Beverly Hills.
目前下落不明 前法式七五成员
Currently M.I.A. Former French 75.
15年前做了污点证人
She went into witness protection about 15 years ago,
后来就消失了
only to disappear.
逮捕她的警官
The arresting agent...
正是史蒂文·勒喉乔上校
Colonel Steven J. Lockjaw.
有些报告说她在古巴
Agency sightings have her in Cuba or Algiers,
也有人说她在阿尔及尔
depending on the report.
看来 她没有母爱
So...not the mothering type, I take it.
他们还好意思说我们野蛮
And they call us the savages.
勒喉乔把自己染脏了
Lockjaw got his dick dirty.
他正在清洗自己
He needs to clean it.
如果他能找到孩子
If he can find this kid,
他就能消灭证据
He can dispose of the evidence,
继续把我们耍得团团转
And continue to make fools out of all of us.
您希望我做什么？
What would you like me to do, sir?
提姆 你很擅长解决家庭案件
Tim, given your expertise in family cases,
我们希望你...
we felt that maybe--
处理干净
Make it clean.
干净？
Clean?
要干净到地板都能当镜子
We should all be able to eat off the floor.
对 要不留痕迹
Yeah. It's that clean.
遵命
Yes, sir.
好了 先生们 我该去西部了
Well, all right, gents. Looks like I'm headed west.
愿圣尼古拉保佑你
And may Saint Nick be with you.
向圣尼古拉敬礼
All hail Saint Nick.
我能问你一件事吗？
I have something to ask you, okay?
问吧
'Kay.
她是叛徒吗？
Was she a rat?
对 她是
Yeah, she was.
我爸爸说她是个英雄
My dad told me she was a hero.
不要撞脑袋 不要撞脑袋
Hey, stop banging your head. Stop banging your head.
不要再撞脑袋了
Stop banging your head on that.
好吧
Okay.
先生 你姓什么？
Sir, do you know your last name?
不知道
No.
你叫什么？
What's your last name?
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
别闹了 赶紧说实话
Okay, come on. I need to know your real last name.
帕克 彼得·帕克
Um, Parker. Peter Parker, man.
【彼得·帕克：虚构人物 蜘蛛侠本名】
彼得·帕克
Peter Parker.
- 对 - 听着 你不想罪名加重的话
- Yeah. - All right, listen. This is your last chance. If you don't give me your real last name,
- 最好乖乖说实话 - 好好好
- it's gonna be another charge. What is it? - Okay, okay.
别再念叨了 烦死了
Stop harassing me, for God sakes!
帕克 我叫吉姆·帕克
Parker. Jim Parker, man.
你叫吉姆·帕克？
Your name's Jim Parker?
对
Yeah.
好 吉姆 你的出生日期
Okay, Jim. What's your date of birth?
大概是一九八几年
I'm somewhere in the '80s, man.
八零后
In the '80s.
对
Yeah.
该走了 到你了
Let's go. You're up.
该走了
Let's go.
起来 老实点儿
Get up. Well, fuck.
坐下
Sit down there.
你是吉姆·帕克先生吗？
Mr. Jim Parker, is that correct?
42岁
Forty-two years old?
她要从身后测量你的生命体征
Sir, she's gonna be taking your vitals behind you, okay?
帕克先生
Mr. Parker.
请看这儿 先生
Mr. Parker, over here.
你有既往病史吗？
Do you have any medical problems?
有
Yeah.
帕克先生 请看着我
Mr. Parker, can you look at me, sir?
鲍勃 能看着我吗？
Bob. Can you look at me?
你有糖尿病吗？
Are you diabetic?
有糖尿病吗？
嗯
Uh-huh.
是吗？
Yeah.
你昨天打胰岛素了吗？
Did you take your insulin yesterday?
你要是有糖尿病
You know, if you're a bad hombre,
必须每天都打胰岛素 知道吗？
You make sure you take your insulin on a daily basis. Right?
警官 这里检查不了 他得去急救室
Officer, we're not gonna be able to take this one. He needs to go out to the ER.
谢谢配合 再见
Thank you, sir. Have a good day.
嗨 你好吗？
Hey, how's it goin'?
- 挺好的 你呢？ - 也挺好
- Good. How are you? - Good, thanks.
帕克先生 这边是卫生间
Mr. Parker, here's your restroom, okay?
来查查血糖
Let's check your sugar.
穿过卫生间就是走廊
You are gonna go through the bathroom,
走到头 再右转 就是逃生梯
straight down the hall to the right to the fire escape.
现在就走
Right now.
现在？
Right now?
现在
Right now.
♪ 赶快 准备好 ♪
♪ Ready, get ready ♪
警官 请帮我签一下住院表格
Hey, Officer. You wanna come sign this intake form with me?
♪ 有没有准备好 我都要来了
♪ Ready or not, here I come ♪
♪ 你无处可逃 ♪
♪ You can't hide ♪
♪ 我会找到你
♪ Gonna find you ♪
♪ 用幸福包围你 ♪
♪ And keep you happy ♪
♪ 有没有准备好 我都要来了
♪ Ready or not, here I come ♪
倒霉
God!
♪ 你无处可逃 ♪
♪ You can't hide ♪
♪ 我要爱着你
♪ Gonna love you ♪
嘿 鲍勃
Hey, Bob!
♪ 让你也爱上我 ♪
♪ And make you love me ♪
大师 我的兄弟 天啊
Sensei, man! Sensei, brother! Oh, my God.
大师 太谢谢你了
Sensei, thank you.
♪ 你别想逃避
♪ You can't run away ♪
谢谢你兄弟 太感谢你了
Thank you, brother. Thank you!
- 谢谢你 谢谢 - 来喝点儿 好啦
- Thank you! - Hey. Here, have one.
♪ 逃不掉我的爱 宝贝
♪ From this love I got, oh baby ♪
老天啊
Oh, my God.
好了 一起拍张照
All right. Let's do a selfie.
♪ 宝贝 因为我有很多爱 ♪
♪ Hey baby, 'cause I got a lot, yeah ♪
我的天啊 真是 什么？
Oh, my God, you got... you got a what?
好的 成功了 逃出来了
Okay. we did it. We did it.
♪ 无论你去哪里
♪ Anywhere you go ♪
- 咱们赶紧走吧 赶紧走 - 要去哪儿？
- Let's get out of here, man. - Where we goin'?
♪ 我的心都会找到你 ♪
♪ My poor heart's gotta know, oh baby ♪
勇敢海狸修女会 卓柏卡布拉山
Sisters of the Brave Beaver. Chupacabra Hills.
- 卓柏卡布拉山 - 开始行动
- Chupacabra Hills. - Let's play offense.
♪ 你无法躲藏我的爱 ♪
♪ Hey baby, you can't hide from my love, no ♪
导航 勇敢海狸修女会
Siri, Sisters of the Brave Beaver.
正在导航 勇敢海狸修女会
Getting directions to the Sisters...
卓柏卡布拉山
Chupacabra Hills.
♪ 有没有准备好 我都要来了 ♪
♪ Ready or not, here I come ♪
好了 我居然救了法式七五的成员
Okay. Not every day you get to rescue a 75er
♪ 我会找到你
♪ Gonna find you ♪
还一天救了两次
Twice in the same day!
走吧 开始行动
Let's rock and fuckin' roll!
♪ 用幸福包围你 ♪
♪ And keep you happy ♪
好
Yeah!
出发
Let's go!
♪ 有没有准备好
♪ Ready or not ♪
♪ 我都要来了
♪ Here I come ♪
♪ 你无处可逃 ♪
♪ You can't hide ♪
♪ 我要爱着你
♪ Gonna love you ♪
♪ 让你也爱上我 ♪
♪ And make you love me ♪
还有吗？
Any more?
没有了 他在这儿
No, sir. He's right here.
♪ 无论你去哪里
♪ Anywhere you go ♪
墨西哥胖子
Buddha bean.
♪ 我的心都会找到你 ♪
♪ My poor heart's gotta know, oh baby ♪
我是史蒂文·勒喉乔上校
Sir, I'm Colonel Steve Lockjaw.
♪ 你无法躲藏我的爱 ♪
♪ Hey baby, you can't hide from my love, no ♪
你最好别耍我
I'm not to be fucked with.
你有什么线索 快点说
You got information for me, spit it out.
我看到一辆灰色面包车 沿克劳溪路向北走
I saw a car, a gray van heading north, up Craw Creek Road.
车上有谁？
Carrying?
看不清楚
Couldn't tell.
开车的是白人 带着个黑人女孩
White man driving, Black girl passenger.
♪ 赶快 准备好 ♪
♪ Ready, get ready ♪
北边 山里有什么？
North. What's in these hills?
♪ 赶快 准备好 ♪
♪ Ready, get ready ♪
勇敢海狸修女会
Sisters of the Brave Beaver.
里面有谁？
Who are they?
一群修女 种大麻的
They grow weed. They're nuns.
♪ 有没有准备好
♪ Ready or not ♪
什么？你在拿上帝开低俗玩笑吗？
Is that some kind of sick joke on God?
♪ 我都要来了
♪ Here I come ♪
♪ 你无处可逃 ♪
♪ You can't hide ♪
我是说真的
I'm not joking.
♪ 我会找到你
♪ Gonna find you ♪
有多少修女？
How many women?
我也不清楚 十几二十个吧
I don't know. A bunch. Ten or 20.
♪ 用幸福包围你 ♪
♪ And keep you happy ♪
♪ 你最好接受 宝贝 ♪
♪ You better come on, baby ♪
有武器吗？
Weapons?
她们应该不杀生
I think they're vegetarian.
♪ 你逃不掉的... ♪
♪ Okay okay... ♪
都听着 使命召唤 准备行动
Men, let's do what we do.
二组 这里是一组
Delta-Two, this is Delta-One.
请侦查
We need to pull imagery.
西北十公里处的山脉 收到
Mountain chain, ten kilometers northwest. How copy?
举起手来
Hands, hands, hands!
解散
Dismissed.
过来
Come closer.
现场亲子鉴定仪
如果不匹配的话 我就放你走
If this doesn't line up, you'll go free.
但如果匹配的话
But if it does line up...
如果连成横线
if this is a straight line...
现场亲子鉴定仪
你就有麻烦了
you got a problem.
这是什么？
What is it?
你的未来
It's your future.
现场亲子鉴定仪
你今年多大？
How old are you now?
你不是十六岁 就是十七岁
You're 16 or 17. It's either one of those.
有男朋友吗？
You have a boyfriend?
我不想和你说话
I don't have anything to say to you.
你这么小 肯定没有男朋友
You're too young to have a boyfriend, so the answer's no.
不要替我回答
Don't answer for me.
这下我懂了
It all makes sense.
你把她从高中救走
You snag her out of the high school.
找到她的手机
Find her phone.
并毁掉了它
Curb stomp that.
眼看就要没事了 却在这个破修道院
But then you fumble her on the 90-yard line
被我们抓到了
at some stank-ass nunnery? Mm!
真是遗憾啊
That's gotta hurt.
你帮我的话 我就会帮你
You help me, I'll help you.
告诉我上哪儿找帕特·卡尔霍恩
You give me Pat Calhoun...
也叫“火箭男”和“穷鬼帕特”
The Rocket Man, Ghetto Pat...
我就送你回家 去救那女孩
And I'll let you go home, and I'll let you save that little girl.
她现在就在上校那儿
You know she's with the Colonel, right?
忘说了
By "home"...
送你回家就是回监狱
I do mean federal prison for you.
你强奸了她吗？
Did you rape her?
你觉得我们是父女吗？
Do you think you're my daughter?
你爱她吗？
Did you love her?
回答我 你觉得我们是父女吗？
Answer me! Do you think you're my daughter?
测试结果不重要
It doesn't matter what that test says.
我有爸爸 可不是你
I have a father, and it's not you.
得了吧 你妈都觉得那人能力不行
Is that what you call a father? He wasn't enough for your mother.
你又怎么会崇拜他呢？
How's he gonna be enough for you?
现场亲子鉴定仪
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
我可以对天发誓 我不知道
I swear, I don't know. I don't know.
迪安德拉 这种话我听过太多次了
Deandra, you know how many people sit across
耳朵都快起茧了
from me and swear to God...
你们都爱说
They don't know?
“我发誓我不知道”
"I swear to God, I don't know."
我也发誓 如果你知道
I swear to God if you do know,
就能救那个女孩
We can save that girl.
那女孩是无辜的
The girl didn't do anything, and I don't know.
我真不知道帕特在哪儿
I don't know where he is.
我要是知道就说了
If I knew where he was, I would tell you.
但我真不知道
I don't know where he is.
你怎么回事？
What the fuck's wrong with you?
告诉我帕特在哪儿
Where is he?
你就能活着去坐牢
Save yourself, go to prison,
我带着消息去找上校
I'll take it to the Colonel,
那女孩就能得救
You save the girl.
棋局已定 你无路可选了
Those are your options. You're in a lose-lose,
就看你想不想保住小命了
maybe-save-your-life position.
你应该多化化妆 让自己好看点儿
You should put on more makeup to make yourself look better.
舞会这样重要的场合
You go to a dance,
不能犯懒
you make an effort.
必须好好化妆
You put on more makeup.
你的衬衫怎么那么紧？
Why is your shirt so tight?
你不要乱猜 我可不是基佬
I'm not gay, if that's what you're sayin'.
我可没这么说
I didn't say that.
反正我不是同性恋
I'm not a homosexual.
这是你提的
I did not say that,
但我确实发现你穿了增高鞋垫
But I see the lifts in your shoes.
你以为自己很聪明吗？
Oh, you are a smartass.
真是太典型了
You... Oh, yeah, yeah.
你就是个娇生惯养的小公主
You just, you're just a little princess, aren't you?
就会耍嘴皮子
Smart mouth. Like your mother.
你妈嘴巴也很毒 最后还是被我征服了
Your mother had a smart mouth, and I buried her.
真聪明 又要看说明书 刚说过就忘了吗？
Are you having trouble remembering what you just read?
如果连成横线 我就有麻烦了
If it's a straight line, I have a problem.
如果不是 就放我走
If it's not, you have to let me go.
你不可能是我爸爸
God, there's no way I'm actually yours,
因为我没这么笨
'cause I can actually fucking read.
够了 闭上你的臭嘴
You shut up. Just shut up!
你就是个小杂种
You fucking mutt!
坏了
Uh-oh.
把我车开来 箱子放上面
Get my vehicle. Put my kid in the car.
我从没想过这混蛋还会回来抓我们
Just never thought this fucker would come back for us, you know?
是我大意了 没有好好防范
I got lazy, man. I wasn't payin' attention.
我没想过这混蛋会回来
I thought the person comin' through that door one day
倒是想过她妈叛娅可能会回来
was gonna be her mom, not this fuckin' asshole.
我以为她会回来看女儿 教她一些女孩的事儿
See her daughter, you know, she'd teach her girl stuff,
给她扎个头发
She'd do her hair, she'd...
做回妈妈
Be a mom.
我不懂怎么帮她扎头发
I can't do her hair, man.
你知道吗？
You know that?
我怎么也扎不好
I don't know how to do her hair right.
是吗？
Well...
别太伤感了 鲍勃
Don't go dark on me, Bob.
好吧
I won't.
好了 没事了
I'm here. I'm here.
把酒收起来 兄弟
Bring it down, bro.
【车内喝酒：美国大多数州禁止驾驶员和乘客 在车内打开或饮用酒精饮料容器】
真是倒霉
Motherfucker.
麻烦来了
Here he comes.
把这藏你包里
Put this in your backpack.
看来咱们完蛋了 是吧？
Guess this is the end of the line, huh?
你还没完
Not for you.
心如止水 平静 平静
Ocean waves. Ocean waves.
我得让你下车了 好兄弟
I gotta ditch you, Kemosabe.
- 什么？ - 你必须走过去
- What? - You gotta hit it on foot.
走过去？
On foot?
对
Yeah.
听我说
Here we go.
我会在前面加油站转弯
I'm gonna turn at this gas station,
然后降低车速
I'm gonna slow down,
你跳下车
and you tuck and roll.
剩下交给我
I'll take it from there.
解开安全带 准备好
Unbuckle and get ready.
- 跳下车 - 对
- Tuck and roll. - Yeah.
好
Okay.
知道自由本质是什么吗？
You know what freedom is?
是什么？
What?
就是不害怕
No fear.
就像是...
Just like...
酷毙的阿汤哥那样
Tom fuckin' Cruise.
【阿汤哥：汤姆·克鲁斯好莱坞动作巨星 以高风险亲自完成特技闻名】
听我数到四就跳 一
Okay. Jump on four. One...
二
...two...
把枪给我
Give me the gun!
三
...three...
跳
Go!
四
Four!
慢点儿
Slow down!
跳啊
Go!
跳啊 鲍勃
Four, Bob!
快点儿跳
Go, four!
起来 得走了
Get up! We're leaving.
你怨我没有陪过你
Making up for lost time?
想让我陪你玩游戏
Little daddy-daughter games?
玩警察抓小偷是吗?
Daddy-daughter games?
我可是圣诞先驱
I am a Christmas Adventurer!
知道那意味着什么吗？
Do you know what that is?
放开我
No!
我有更崇高的使命
I have a higher calling.
跟我的使命相比
It is a higher honor
你的小命根本不算什么
than having you.
遇敌 遇敌 十二点钟方向
Contact, contact! 12 o'clock!
老实说 我爱过她
I loved her, in case you were wonderin'.
你妈是我这辈子见过的
Best goddamn-looking
最漂亮的黑妞
witch I ever saw.
住嘴
Shut up.
可惜 那时她着魔了
Yeah, she was possessed.
- 闭上你的臭嘴 - 是个激进的疯子
- Shut the fuck up. - She was insane.
很像你 你跟她一模一样
Like you. You have it in you.
她身上有疯子的味儿 你身上也有
I smelled it from within her, and I can smell it from within you.
她是个该死的叛徒
She was a fucking rat.
她是个战士
She was a warrior,
一心一意为了自由而战
A righteous warrior of freedom!
她碾压所有的弱者
And she fought the weak!
她是个该死的叛徒
She was a fucking rat!
你应该学会尊重自己的父母
You should respect your mother and your father both.
我真该好好教教你
Poke your fuckin' eyes out.
阿威腾
Avanti.
最近生意怎么样？
How's the bounty business?
还行吧 你最近怎样？
It's all right. How's it with you?
说不上很理想
Things could be better.
麻烦一桩接一桩
It's not one thing, it's a-fuckin'-nother.
能理解这种感觉吗？
Do you find that to be true?
总之
Anyway...
我得处理掉这个麻烦
I need to dispose of this one.
是谁？
Who is it?
杀人嫌犯 拉丁狗混血
Murder suspect. Wetback half-breed.
干过非法贸易 死了也没人在乎
Involved in narco cartels. Nobody that will be missed.
不行 我不杀小孩
That's a kid. I don't do kids.
小孩也会犯罪
Kids do bad shit.
你干吗不自己动手？
Why don't you do it?
我没时间 得找人替我
I can't do it. I'm busy. So who can do it?
你可以找埃里克·割罗
Well, get Erik Garrow to do it.
我不想找埃里克·割罗
I don't want Erik Garrow to do it.
干掉她 我付你双倍酬劳
I'll pay you double your daily rate, get this done.
那也不行 我不干
I don't give a shit. I'm not doin' it.
好吧
All right.
知道一七七六吗？
You know the 1776,
离德尔里奥有8公里 靠近沃特兰
about five miles outside Del Rio by Walter's Landing?
- 知道 - 好
- Yeah. - Yeah.
把她送过去 每天多少钱按定好的给你
You get her to them, I'll pay you your daily rate.
耍小聪明
Smart aleck.
死丫头 一点儿规矩都不知道
You got no manners, God damn it!
没家教的玩意儿
You weren't raised right!
看到了吗？看见没有？
You see that?! You see that?!
你妈就这么教你的
That's what your mother brought up.
进去
Get... there.
很好 小兔崽子
Kick all the way.
你就闹吧 再大点儿劲
Yeah, go ahead, kick! Kick, kick!
我也不想做得这么绝
I'm sorry it had to end this way.
你要是听话 咱俩还能聊聊
If you had any manners, we might have gotten to know each other.
小兔崽子
Little bitch child.
真该死
Bitch child.
跟她妈一样的坏黑妞
All goddamn witches...
死混蛋 你想带我去什么地方？
Where the fuck are you taking me, asshole?
会有人过来找你吗？
Someone gonna come by lookin' for you?
问你呢 会有人来找你吗？
I said, is someone gonna come by lookin' for you?
当然
Yeah.
他们会来救我
They're gonna find me,
把你大卸八块
and they're gonna fuck you up.
迪乔治乔路
该死 他们到底去哪儿了？
Fuck, fuck, fuck. Come on.
可恶
Fuck!
去哪儿了？
新鲜水果
（西班牙语）你们好
（西班牙语）你好 兄弟
（西班牙语）你们有没有看到
（西班牙语）一辆黑色SUV？
（西班牙语）上面坐着一个非常年轻的女孩
（西班牙语）还有个看着很坏很坏的男人
新鲜水果
（西班牙语）往那边开了
（西班牙语）- 那边？ - 那边
（西班牙语）不是那边吗？
（西班牙语）那边 往右拐
（西班牙语）谢谢你们 谢谢
低头
Head.
提起外套 转身
All right, lift your shirt and turn around.
把手举过头顶
Put your hands on top of your head.
快点搜吧
All right, let's go to work.
不要动 你有带武器吗？
Do not move. Do you have any weapons on you, sir?
没有 警官
No, sir.
你为什么要逃跑？
Why are you running from us?
我累糊涂了 警官
Had a long day, ma'am.
你没看到警灯吗？
You didn't see the lights back there?
看到了
Yes, I did.
你往车外扔了什么？
What did you toss out of the vehicle?
什么？
'Scuse me?
你刚才往车外扔了什么？
What did you toss out of the vehicle back there?
垃圾
Trash.
你确定吗？
You sure about that?
确定 警官
Yes, ma'am.
你今天喝酒了？
You been drinking today?
喝了一点儿
I've had a few.
一点是多少？
A few what?
就几罐啤酒
Few small beers.
【酒类法律：美国大多数州酒驾将罚款 吊照 严重或累犯可拘留起诉】
警惕山洪
找到了
There you are.
看到你了
I see you.
终于找到了
找到你了
I got you,
混蛋 等着瞧吧
motherfucker, I got you.
破车 别慢腾腾的
Faster, you fuckin' piece of shit!
快点儿
Go!
哪冒出的混蛋
Who's this asshole?
你想干吗？
What do you want?
（残酷无情）
是勒喉乔送来的吗？
Is that from Lockjaw?
来处理尸体
We got a body.
收到 收到
Copy, copy.
谢啦 印第安佬
Thanks, wagon-burner.
该死
Fuck.
可恶
不是吧
Oh, no.
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
可恶
God damn it.
该死
Fuck.
可恶
Fuck!
（残酷无情）
嘿 蠢货 你要干吗？
Hey, fuckstick, what are ya doin'?
傻土著 别装聋子
Hey, Red, I know you hear me.
梅里克商行
爱计较者出门左转不送
售卖冰块
【ICE：美国移民和海关执法局同样缩写为ICE 负责美国境内移民和海关执法任务】
酒喝多了 脑子喝残了？
That firewater's got you fuckin' retarded.
天啊
Oh, God.
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!
Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!
“新青...”
Green..."
薇拉
Willa!
可恶
Fuck.
转过去 转过去
Please, please.
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
该死
Fuck!
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!"
什么？
What?!
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!"
我不知道
I don't know--
快说
Say it!
薇拉
Willa?
Willa!
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!"
不 不 宝贝 是我
No, no, no, baby, it's me.
薇拉 是我
Willa, it's...
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!"
好的
Okay!
好
爸爸来了 薇拉
It's your dad, Willa!
“上层建筑再也不重要了”
"Will no longer be so goddamn relevant."
看看我
Look at me.
你这白男是谁？
Who are you?
我是你爸爸
It's your dad!
仔细看
Look at me.
没事了
It's okay.
没事
没受伤吧 宝贝？
Are you okay?
你没事吧？伤着了吗？
都还好吧？
Are you okay?
好了 快上车 快点儿
Come on. Go to the car. Go!
走吧 我们走
Let's go. Let's go.
♪ （西班牙语）孤独
太可怕了
Oh, my God.
♪ （西班牙语）让我在焦虑中颤抖 ♪
已经没事儿了 放心吧
You're okay now. You're okay.
♪ （西班牙语）每个人
♪ （西班牙语）都对我不闻不问 ♪
♪ （西班牙语）女人
♪ （西班牙语）你可问问上天
♪ （西班牙语）是否曾有一刻
♪ （西班牙语）我对你爱意消减 ♪
♪ （西班牙语）大海
♪ （西班牙语）映出我的内心
♪ （西班牙语）深知我曾几度哭泣
♪ （西班牙语）只因你无情背叛 ♪
你认识黑人激进分子
Do you know a Black militant by the name of
叛娅·富山吗？
Perfidia Beverly Hills?
认识
Yes, I do.
她难道不是反动组织法式七五的成员吗？
And was she a member of the rebel group known as the French 75?
是的
She was.
噢
Yeah.
勒喉乔上校
Colonel Lockjaw...
你是不是和她 有过不正当的男女关系？
did you engage in a romantic relationship with this woman?
♪ （西班牙语）可是你
♪ （西班牙语）谁知道你身在何处
先生们
Gentlemen...
我曾在战场上与敌人正面厮杀
I have engaged the enemy face-to-face in battle.
也曾在阴暗角落跟间谍斗智斗勇
And in the dark alleys and shadows of espionage.
我曾经被
I was once...
逆向强奸过
raped in reverse.
逆向强奸？
Raped in reverse?
能请你解释一下
Could you explain how that might...
那是什么意思吗？
work for us, Colonel Lockjaw?
我不小心被敌军骗了 被下了药
The enemy employed deception. I was drugged.
我失去了意识
And while unconscious...
大脑无法正常工作
My brain was not working.
但我的雄风仍在 所以被敌军占了便宜
But my power was, and I believe it was taken advantage of.
你有证据吗？
What kind of proof do you have?
如果没有意识 你怎么知道的？
If you were unconscious, how do you know this to be true?
我是推测出来的
I don't know it to be true, but I suspect it.
我醒来后 觉得那里有点儿不舒服
When I awoke, there was sensitivity in a private place,
还发现了那种事的痕迹
and there was some residue of an interaction.
那种事？
Interaction?
她偷了我的生命之源
I believe she was a sperm thief.
偷精生子
A semen demon.
没错
That's correct.
勒喉乔上校
Colonel Lockjaw,
敌军为什么要大费周章逆向强奸 怀你的孩子？
What would be the purpose of the enemy raping you in reverse?
我的心智与体魄充满了威能
They saw the power of my mind and body.
他们馋得不行
They desired it.
祝贺你 史蒂文
Congratulations, Steve.
你成功加入了圣诞先驱俱乐部
You're a Christmas Adventurer.
妈呀 谢谢您 先生
Oh, Mommy. Thank you, sir.
我带你参观一下西南总部
Let me show you around southwest headquarters.
好啊
Sure.
我们走吧
Should we go for a walk?
好的
Yes, sir.
参观第一站
First stop on the tour,
你的新办公室
your new office.
天啊
Oh, my.
说实话 桑迪先生
You know, if I'm being honest, Sandy,
有那么一刻 我还以为自己失败了
there was a minute there where I didn't think I was gonna make it.
勒喉乔 有你加入是我们的幸事
Lockjaw, we're lucky to have you.
好了 如你所见 大家都不在
Now, obviously, goes without saying,
这个办公室只是给你挂挂帽子
this is just one place where you can hang your hat,
开开会 放放个人物品的地方
take meetings, stow a few personal items.
我们希望每个成员都在总部有个家
We like our members to feel they have a home away from home,
随时都可以回来
any time, day or night.
这个理念太棒了
That's a fine idea.
办公室现在还空着
Now, it's empty right now,
但你可以自己布置
But we'll let you personalize it.
一个人的品味是最重要的
A man's taste defines him, doesn't it?
您说得太对了
It does indeed, sir.
好的 我们到了
And here we are.
第55套间
Suite 55.
看看这景色
Look at that view.
真是太美了
Would you look at that?
我能进吗？
May I?
当然可以
Absolutely.
糟糕 忘了拿你的钥匙
Damn it. I forgot your keys.
在这儿等着 我这就回办公室拿
Wait here, I'll just grab 'em from my office.
遵命
Yes, sir.
有一样东西 在我这儿保管很久了
I've been holding on to something for a while now
现在我想把它给你
and I wanted to give it to you.
好吗？
Okay?
之前没有给你是因为...
And I didn't give it to you before because I...
我不想让你过早地接触这些事情
I just didn't wanna expose you to certain stuff.
说实话我不想让你...
You know, I didn't want you to feel...
伤心
sad...
或者为这些事烦恼
or confused about it.
我不知道我想要什么
I don't know. I don't know what I wanted.
我只是
I wanted...
我想要保护你
I wanted to protect you.
不要受你妈妈的影响
From all your mom's shit.
也别受我影响
From all my shit.
我大概只是想 当个好爸爸
I just, I suppose I wanted to be the one
这样 你有困难的时候会来找我帮忙
that you came to for help, right?
当一个很酷的爸爸
You know, the one, the cool dad
能让你敞开心扉
that you could say anything to.
虽然我知道这是不可能的
Even though I know that's impossible.
【火化：违背传统福音派的葬制 历史上用作对异己的净化与消灭】
但我不想
But I don't want...
我不想对你撒谎 以后再也不会了
I don't wanna lie to you about anything anymore.
【毒气室与焚化：对应纳粹时期的制度化灭绝 暗示对他者的系统性权利剥夺】
我保管它已经好多年了
And I've been holdin' on to somethin' for a couple years now
不过现在
and I just wanna...
我想把它交给你
I just wanna give it to you.
好吧 我这就拿出来
Okay, I'm gonna share this with you
那个 要是你想看
and if you wanna see it,
你就看
You can see it.
你要看吗？
Do you wanna see it?
我都不知道那是什么 爸爸
I don't know what it is, Dad.
你猜不到是什么？
You don't know what it is?
猜不到
No.
这是 一封信
It's a letter.
是你妈妈写来的信
It's a letter from your mom.
是给我的 还是给你的？
Is it for me or for you?
是给你的
It's for you.
你想一个人看对吗？
You wanna go read it alone?
去吧
Go ahead.
“亲爱的夏琳
Dear Charlene...
“我从远影里向你问好”
Hello from the other side of the shadows.
“我不想吓到你
I don't mean to shock you,
“但我真的一直想要给你写信”
but I've been contemplatin' writin' you for a long time.
“有时醒来 感觉很不真实
I often wake up and I find it completely crazy how
“我怎么会
and why I am where
“会变成今天这样？”
I am today.
“和家人都断了联系”
And disconnected from my family.
“我的一生都在假装
I pretended my whole life.
“假装坚强
I pretended to be strong...
“假装已死”
pretended to be dead.
“我说了那么多谎话 还能面对你吗？”
Is it too late for us, after all my lies?
“你过得开心吗？
Are you happy?
“有没有爱的人？”
Do you have love?
“等你长大了想要做什么？”
What will you do when you get older?
“你会像我一样想改变世界吗？”
Will you try to change the world, like I did?
“我们失败了
We failed.
“但也许你不会
But maybe you will not.
“也许你能让世界变得更好”
Maybe you will be the one who puts the world right.
“我每天都在想你
I think of you every single day...
“每天”
every single day.
“真希望那时我能为我们母女撑起一片新天地”
And I wish I had been strong for the both of us.
“我知道有一天
I know someday...
“等时机合适 安全的时候
when it's right and it's safe...
“你会找到我”
you will find me.
“替我吻一下你爸爸
Please send a kiss to your dad...
“我的穷鬼帕特”
my Ghetto Pat.
“爱你的妈妈
Love, your mom,
“叛娅”
Perfidia.
帮我看看自拍闪光灯 应该怎么用的
How do I get this flash to work?
照不到我的脸
It's not gettin' my face.
怎么才能让闪光灯照到我的脸？
I don't know how to get it to get my face.
上面有一个闪电符号
Swipe up, and then there's a lightning bolt.
点一下会出来
And then on there,
闪光灯 自动 打开 关闭
it says, "Flash auto on and off."
不闪啊
No.
那么你就按一下...
Well, if you push the...
哪儿有个...
There's a little...
右下角应该有个按钮切换到自拍 你点一下
There's a little circle on the bottom right side. Click that.
或者用后置摄像头拍
Okay. Or take it with the back.
都可以
I guess that's fine.
- “通告 重要通告” - 右下角按钮是吗？
- QST, QST. - I gotta press the circle.
“这里是N6-EDG
This is N6EDG,
“来自奥克兰的‘威士忌酸酒’”
the Whiskey Sour in Oakland.
“‘威士忌酸酒’进行全台通告”
QST signal from the Whiskey Sour in Oakland.
他是说奥克兰吗？
Did they say Oakland?
- “人类联盟正在突袭” - 对
- MKU raids in progress. - Yeah.
瑟
吉
奥
·
圣
卡
洛
斯
忍
者
学
院
“重复 人类联盟正在突袭”
Repeat, MKU raids in progress.
“抗议集合点在林肯公园”
Meeting point for protesters is Lincoln Park.
“全台通告 这里是‘威士忌酸酒’”
QST, this is the Whiskey Sour.
“大家都快来
All hands on deck.
“这里是N6-EDG”
N6EDG.
我说 开车去奥克兰 可要三个半小时呢
You know, Oakland's a three-and-a-half-hour drive from here.
知道
Yeah.
那可够远的
You know that's far, right?
还下着雨呢
Well, it's raining out.
嘿
Hey!
小心点儿
Be careful.
才不要
I won't.
一
战
再
♪ 她是一个美国女孩
♪ Well, she was an American girl ♪
编剧及导演
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h保罗·托马斯·安德森
♪ 从小到大充满希望 ♪
♪ Raised on promises ♪
制片人
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h亚当·索姆纳
♪ 她忍不住想
♪ She couldn't help thinkin' that there ♪
♪ 在别的地方
♪ Was a little more to life ♪
制片人
萨拉·墨菲
保罗·托马斯·安德森
♪ 还有更精彩人生 ♪
♪ Somewhere else ♪
主演
莱昂纳多·迪卡普里奥
饰 父亲鲍勃
♪ 毕竟 这世界多么广阔
♪ After all It was a great big world ♪
主演
西恩·潘
饰 上校勒喉乔
♪ 有太多地方值得一去
♪ With lots of places to run to ♪
主演
本尼西奥·德尔·托罗
饰 柔道大师圣卡洛斯
♪ 如果她一生只能止于尝试
♪ Yeah, and if she had to die tryin' ♪
主演
雷吉娜·赫尔
饰 接应人迪安德拉
♪ 那她心中还有个
♪ She had one little promise ♪
♪ 小小的希望 ♪
♪ She was gonna keep ♪
主演
缇雅娜·泰勒
饰 母亲叛娅
♪ 噢耶 ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
主演
蔡斯·英菲尼迪
饰 女儿薇拉
♪ 没错 ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ 慢一点儿 宝贝 ♪
♪ Take it easy, baby ♪
制作公司
古拉迪影业
♪ 持续一整夜 ♪
♪ Make it last all night ♪
♪ 她是一个美国女孩 ♪
♪ She was an American girl ♪
出品公司
华纳兄弟影业
联合出品
领域娱乐
摄影
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h迈克尔·鲍曼
♪ 那一晚有些寒冷
♪ Well, it was kind of cold that night ♪
艺术指导
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h弗洛伦西亚·马丁
♪ 她独自站在阳台上 ♪
♪ She stood alone on her balcony ♪
剪辑
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h安迪·贾尔根森
♪ 耳边传来阵阵车声
♪ Yeah, she could hear the cars roll by ♪
配乐
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h强尼·格林伍德
♪ 441号公路车流不息
♪ Out on four forty-one ♪
字幕译制
上海电影译制厂
蒙太奇字幕组
♪ 就像浪潮拍打着海岸 ♪
♪ Like waves crashin' on the beach ♪
翻译
上海电影译制厂: 许诺 & 徐子怡
蒙太奇字幕组 : 小p & 十三
♪ 在那绝望的时刻
♪ And for one desperate moment there ♪
蒙太奇字幕组
双语合并：novaeye & 小p & NickCollect & Lei
时间轴：小p & novaeye
校对：小p & 十三 & novaeye & NickCollect
♪ 她逃回了记忆之中 ♪
♪ He crept back in her memory ♪
蒙太奇字幕组
注释：小p & 十三
后期特效：NickCollect
♪ 这一切多么悲伤
♪ God, it's so painful ♪
蒙太奇字幕组
Telegram和IRC交流群：MontageSubs
♪ 明明近在咫尺
♪ Something that's so close ♪
蒙太奇字幕组字幕许可
原创部分许可CC BY‑NC‑SA 4.0
♪ 却触不可及 ♪
♪ And still so far out of reach ♪
影片灵感源于托马斯·品钦所著小说
《葡萄园》
♪ 噢耶 ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ 没错 ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ 慢一点儿 宝贝 ♪
♪ Take it easy, baby ♪
♪ 持续一整夜 ♪
♪ Make it last all night ♪
♪ 她是一个美国女孩 ♪
♪ She was an American girl ♪
♪ 你没法在家坐视不管 哥们儿 ♪
♪ You will not be able to stay home, brother ♪
♪ 你没法打开电视逃避现实 ♪
♪ You will not be able to plug in turn on and cop out ♪
♪ 你没法用药物来麻痹掩目 ♪
♪ You will not be able to lose yourself on skag ♪
♪ 你没法在广告时间出门买啤酒 因为
♪ And skip out for beer during commercials because ♪
♪ 革命永远不会被喉舌转播 ♪
♪ The revolution will not be televised ♪
♪ 他们实施的暴力 永远不会播出 ♪
♪ There will be no pictures of pigs shooting down brothers on the instant replay ♪
♪ 要是惠特尼·杨被示众
♪ There will be no pictures of Whitney Young ♪
【惠特尼·杨：黑人民权领袖 此处指当局常以“平息骚乱”名义隐去真实画面】
♪ 电视上绝对没有这场面 ♪
♪ Being run out of harlem on a rail with a brand new process ♪
♪ 你也看不到罗伊·威尔金斯
♪ There will be no slow motion or still lifes of Roy Wilkins ♪
【罗伊·威尔金斯：黑人民权领袖 美国有色人种协进会前任领导人】
♪ 穿着红黑绿的解放服
♪ Strolling through Watts in a red, black and green liberation jumpsuit ♪
【红黑绿解放色：泛非主义旗色 红为血与抗争 黑为非裔身份 绿为非洲土地】
♪ 在镜头前亮相 ♪
♪ That he has been saving for just the proper occasion ♪
【看不到在镜头前亮相：批判媒体美化消费黑人解放并隐去其政治实质】
♪ 新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇 ♪
♪ Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies and Hooterville Junction ♪
♪ 上层建筑再也不重要了 ♪
♪ Will no longer be so damn relevant ♪
♪ 洗脑的肥皂剧
♪ And women will not care if Dick finally got down with Jane ♪
♪ 也洗不掉她们的关切 ♪
♪ On Search for tomorrow ♪
♪ 因为黑人会走上街头 ♪
♪ Because Black people will be in the street ♪
♪ 带着未来的希冀 ♪
♪ Looking for a brighter day ♪
♪ 革命永远不会被喉舌转播 ♪
♪ The revolution will not be televised ♪
♪ 不会被喉舌转播 ♪
♪ Will not be televised ♪
♪ 革命永远不会有重播 ♪
♪ The revolution will be no re-run, brothers ♪
♪ 革命只能在现场看得到 ♪
♪ The revolution will be live ♪
♪ 愿你们得到欢乐
♪ God rest ye merry gentlemen ♪
♪ 愿你们不要沮丧 ♪
♪ Let nothing you dismay ♪
♪ 请记住那位圣人
♪ Remember Christ our savior ♪
♪ 就在圣诞节降生 ♪
♪ Was born on Christmas day ♪
♪ 他救我们远离魔鬼
♪ To save us all from Satan's power ♪
♪ 使我们不致迷途 ♪
♪ When we were gone astray ♪
♪ 平安和欢乐的消息 一路传来 ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy comfort and joy ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy ♪
♪ 从那遥远的天上
♪ From God our heavenly father ♪
♪ 来了一位天使 ♪
♪ A blessed angel came ♪
♪ 他为某个牧羊人
♪ And unto certain shepherds ♪
♪ 带来了好消息 ♪
♪ Brought tidings of the same ♪
♪ 在伯利恒
♪ How bad in Bethlehem was born ♪
♪ 有一位圣人出生了 ♪
♪ The son of God by name ♪
♪ 平安和欢乐的消息 一路传来 ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy comfort and joy ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy ♪
♪ 在场的人
♪ Now to the Lord sing praises ♪
♪ 都高声歌颂 ♪
♪ All you within this place ♪
♪ 团结友爱
♪ And with true love and brotherhood ♪
♪ 拥抱彼此 ♪
♪ Each other now embrace ♪
♪ 圣诞的气氛
♪ This holy tide of Christmas ♪
♪ 消除了不和 ♪
♪ All others doth deface ♪
♪ 平安和欢乐的消息 一路传来 ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy comfort and joy ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy ♪
我能接着拍
I can do it now.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 科林 准备好了吗？ - 好了
- Colin, are you good? - Yeah.
场录 开始录音 开始
And roll sound, roll, roll, please.
（谨以此片献给亚当）
【亚当·索姆纳：于2024年11月去世 曾多次担任导演安德森的副导演】
都请安静 开拍了
Hey, quiet please. Here we go, shooting.
住嘴 我们在拍了
Shut the fuck up, we're rolling.
乐
领域娱乐
开拍
Action.
华纳兄弟影业
蒙 太 奇 字 幕 组(MontageSubs)
用爱发电 ♥\h\hPowered by love